<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What is Bitcoin Mining?</title>
    <description>Become the best Bitcoin miner and learn how to mine Bitcoins with the best Bitcoin mining hardware, software, pools and cloud mining.</description>
    <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.bitcoinmining.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Bitcoin Mining Heart Attack</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Marshall Long, Greg Maxwell, Mark Freidenbach, and Adam Back for related discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue is one which &lt;em&gt;might disable Bitcoin completely&lt;/em&gt;, requiring a (simple) hard fork to get it “unstuck”. This issue becomes more dangerous over the next 20-30 years (likely most dangerous in 2020-2028), but then quickly declines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll break it into two subproblems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;subproblem-1-the-blockreward-halving-instantly-cuts-miner-revenues-by-a-huge-fraction&quot;&gt;SubProblem 1: The blockreward halving instantly cuts miner revenues by a huge fraction.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this assumes [1] that transaction fees are negligible and [2] the Bitcoin exchange rate never increases in response to the difficulty halving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transaction fees are currently around 1% of miner-revenues, and no one expects this proportion to significantly increase anytime soon. Even if transaction fees were 50% of revenues (wildly optimistic), the reward-halving would still cut total revenues by (1/4), a sizable proportion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bitcoin exchange rate is important to miners and shouldn’t change in response to the difficulty halving, at all. By &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Efficient-market_hypothesis&quot;&gt;Weak Efficient Markets&lt;/a&gt;, anyone who believes that the USD/BTC price will imminently double, should be buying immediately (and bidding up the price). Because of “saturation” Bitcoin might have some immunity to the EMH, but (like all EMH-resistance) this immunity is constantly hard at work, canceling itself out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sp-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;sp1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure. On the left, the reward-halving dominates the block-reward; on the right, transaction-fee variance dominates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;subproblem-2-the-difficulty-adjustment-process-causes-miner-homogeneity&quot;&gt;SubProblem 2: The difficulty adjustment process causes miner homogeneity.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every two weeks, the total costs of mining (namely, the difficulty) reset such that the average miner achieves an expected &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/terms/e/economicprofit.asp&quot;&gt;economic profit&lt;/a&gt; of zero. Those in the bottom half can no longer afford to operate, and they (eventually) switch their miners off and drop out of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is an academic simplification of actual mining. It ignores [1] uncertainty (in all factors) and [2] ‘permanent advantages’ (“free” power, geographic distribution of energy sources, ASIC engineering secrets), but those artifacts merely slow the inevitable: this is an ever-present, fundamentally underlying process of filtration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the lower-quality miners get filtered out, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Queen_hypothesis&quot;&gt;the filter reacts to the increase in quality&lt;/a&gt; by becoming more intense. Eventually, only a few top quality miners will remain. These miners might follow &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; best-practices (all the solar-power miners might have a different set of best practices than the hydro-power miners), but &lt;strong&gt;all miners should eventually have tiny, and &lt;u&gt;equal&lt;/u&gt; economic profit margins&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sp-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;sp2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Because an average is just a single number, it necessarily contains less total information than the distribution from whence it came.
--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;combined&quot;&gt;Combined&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is when these effects happen at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/prob.png&quot; alt=&quot;Prob&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, we will reach a day when all miners have small profit margins, and then a blockreward-halving will slash their revenues in half. &lt;strong&gt;The result will be that not half, but &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; miners will shut off their mining rigs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, the difficulty won’t re-adjust (decrease) until (on average) 1008 blocks later. (In fact, we always &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitcoinclock.com/&quot;&gt;know exactly&lt;/a&gt; the number of blocks.) So, even miners who plan to turn their mining rigs back on, post-difficulty-decrease, would have them off for this brief unprofitable period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that it might not be brief. The difficulty adjustment period, which would normally last two weeks, is counted in &lt;em&gt;blocks&lt;/em&gt;, not human-time. So it could actually last forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Or, until someone manually hard-forked the network [to something with 60% difficulty], thus giving the stalled engine a jump.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not all: even if most of the miners stayed on, the resulting uncertainty (or merely the increase in confirmation times) might cause a Bitcoin currency crisis. Abnormal tx-fee and exchange-rate volatility would increase Bitcoin’s risk premium, harming Bitcoin’s value-proposition as money. One example: were the USD/BTC price to fall by half, the blockreward-halving would have an effect more-resembling a blockreward-&lt;em&gt;quartering&lt;/em&gt;. A falling USD/BTC price widens the gulf between mining costs and revenues, and makes the problem &lt;em&gt;even worse&lt;/em&gt;, potentially resulting in a death spiral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the near term, miners are different enough (and the exchange rate is already volatile enough) such that most will survive the halving, and in the long term, Bitcoin might be sufficiently important such that transaction fees simply increase (in step with the higher confirmation times) to offset the problem. However, in the medium term, namely the year 2020, it is potentially disastrous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-wont-work&quot;&gt;What Won’t Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;do-nothing&quot;&gt;Do Nothing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We might hope that miners, out of the kindness of their hearts, would simply keep mining (at a loss) to prevent Bitcoin from dying (and prevent their specialized hardware from depreciating to zero).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t acceptable to me - in equilibrium, miners consume all of their BTC revenues (which are all spent on operating or capital costs), and it is easy to imagine miners who plan their capital investments to align with the 4 year Bitcoin halving cycle (“we’re going to run these into the ground until the reward halves, and then replan from there”). Mining hardware itself rarely lasts longer than 2 years, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of altruistic mining can be roughly estimated. Currently, miners collectively earn 2016*25*300 = over $15 million dollars in revenue each difficulty cycle. These inputs might all change, of course, but, if they didn’t, the 2016 halving would slash this revenue by over $7,000,000. If miners were already running at cost, this 7M figure is the cost of keeping 10 minute blocks. Worse still, such altruism would &lt;em&gt;prevent&lt;/em&gt; the subsequent difficulty adjustment from being representative; miners would only keep themselves trapped in Altruism Prison, losing money the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, “we” are increasingly unable to “help” the miners…ongoing professional hardware-specialization makes our “civilian hardware” (home PCs, phones) overwhelmingly irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;upon-each-blockreward-halving-also-halve-the-difficulty&quot;&gt;Upon Each Blockreward Halving, Also Halve the Difficulty&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly the intent was to cut profits in half, not revenues. Unfortunately, there’s no clear way for the protocol to learn about miner’s profit margins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One (hard fork) idea is to simultaneously halve the difficulty (with the reward); this &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; work, but instead it might simply delay the problem for 2016 blocks (which might all mined in one week, instead of two), at which point the difficulty would double…landing us right back where we started. If ‘halving the difficulty’ perfectly halved the total costs of mining (including overhead and labor), and the blockreward perfectly halved the revenues (ie, transactions fees were nonexistent and the exchange rate never changed), then it might work, but difficulty has a stronger relationship with &lt;strong&gt;time&lt;/strong&gt; that it does with cost (and revenues are driven mostly by Bitcoin’s exchange rate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/in-one-image.png&quot; alt=&quot;ProbImage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that there’s only one way to guarantee that the problem be removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;smooth-the-deflation-out&quot;&gt;Smooth the Deflation Out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only ironclad solution is to replace the sudden halving of the Bitcoin coinbase with a continuous, gradual decrease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/reward-eq.png&quot; alt=&quot;reward-eq&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where r refers to the quantity of BTC released per block, t refers to the block number (ie, “time”), and lambda is some parameter. (Little t is used to index on r, but big T refers to the actual number itself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fork-types&quot;&gt;Fork Types&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be done either with a hard fork or with a soft fork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While any hard fork can replace one issuance policy with another, a soft fork must obey the original issuance rules. This can be done by storing coins in a kind of “softfork reserve account”, with special rules allowing only &lt;em&gt;future&lt;/em&gt; block-finders to withdraw. Because the bank can never have a negative balance under soft fork, such a change would involve some sacrifice on the part of the miners (they’d be losing coins that they’d otherwise be able to keep). A hard fork, freed from the original rules, can reduce this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;details&quot;&gt;Details&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some &lt;a href=&quot;/images/impact-of-reward-change.xlsx&quot;&gt;preliminary Excel math&lt;/a&gt; to take a first look at the potential issuance schedule and its effect on miners. This analysis is oversimplified (a year spans just a single row, instead of 6*24*365 = 52,560 rows), and I would (obviously) improve it before making a formal proposal. The specific numbers are, of course, irrelevant; only the concepts are relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;.&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard Fork&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soft Fork&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lambda (Annual)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;.012&lt;strong&gt;371160&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;.012&lt;strong&gt;166134&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;PV Impact (BTC, at 5%)*&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-81,442.1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-119,080.3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;BTC in Year 2168&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21,038,400.0**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21,038,399.7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20,973,054.6&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Obviously, I used math to minimize this value in each case.
&lt;p&gt;**This value is not 21 million, because of leap years (and other simplifications, which are consistent across scenarios). So, “Hard Fork” is accurately recreating “Original” (and not a second error).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/alt-issuance.png&quot; alt=&quot;Issuance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/btc-reserve.png&quot; alt=&quot;Issuance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soft fork eventually starts accumulating larger-and-larger proportions of tinier-and-tinier blockrewards, such that ~65,000 BTC remain trapped in the bank forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;costs&quot;&gt;Costs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the damage (~ 81/119 ~= 68%) is done whether the fork is soft or hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This damage (the cost to miners, of loaning these coins to the bank without compensation) would be substantial: at a market price of $250/BTC, the 119K BTC are worth nearly $30,000,000 USD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, mining revenues are mostly driven by the exchange rate itself, so we have to weigh this cost against any BTC appreciation that might occur as a result of this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-the-soft-fork-might-work&quot;&gt;How the Soft Fork Might Work&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, the soft fork would still allow miners to “mine” 25 BTC per 10 minutes. Some portion of these 25 would simply be ‘frozen’ (metaphorically, they would be “placed” into a “miner-bank”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We might require the “bank” to be an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Script#Anyone-Can-Spend_Outputs&quot;&gt;‘ANYONE-CAN-SPEND’&lt;/a&gt; BTC address, yet with miners enforcing a pre-specified policy for spending from this address. Later, when someone mines a block that needs to ‘withdraw’ from the bank (during the 2020-2038 years, where the smooth curves are above the blue jagged line) the refined protocol can simply agree to allow a certain number of BTC to be transferred from this address to anywhere (knowing that the winning miner will give it to him or herself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be the first soft fork which is not obviously a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pareto_efficiency&quot;&gt;Pareto improvement&lt;/a&gt;: it harms a subset of individuals (the miners) –if we neglect to consider that miners would also be harmed by Bitcoin’s collapse as a result of this unfixed problem. This is particularly interesting because miners are the very group which turn soft forks on and off. At around year 2020, the ANYONE-CAN-SPEND address will have accumulated over 450,000 BTC (today, worth over $120 million).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent an interesting situation might emerge where miners attempt to raid those funds, possibly by bribing users to upgrade their software, or by lobbying in some other way, notice:
&lt;p&gt;1. Regular users would almost certainly have upgraded their software by then (making this a little more like a hard fork).
&lt;p&gt;2. An un-forked block is too valuable for its own good. Worth more than surrounding blocks by a factor of 72,000 ( = 450,000/6.25), The Block that rewards all these coins would be fought over endlessly (as new miners will most certainly jump online to mine this single block, and then refuse to participate in a chain that does not allow them to win). So, threats to start a fight aren’t very credible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-this-happen&quot;&gt;How did this happen?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems strange to see a design flaw in Bitcoin, something which was otherwise so perfectly-crafted. I’m inclined to think that the inherent fairness of the static “50 BTC per block” appealed to Satoshi; that he anticipated a great deal of criticism off the bat, and didn’t want to be hearing “I don’t want to join this! You’ve already started mining and got all the easiest blocks for yourself!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, it certainly is easier to explain “you get 50 of them with each block, but this number drops by half every four years” than it is to say “ ‘a formula’ determines how many BTC you get”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/bitcoin-mining-heart-attack/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/bitcoin-mining-heart-attack/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Proof of Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/what-is-proof-of-work.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/what-is-proof-of-work-high-resolution.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Visualize and Download High-Resolution Infographic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A proof of work is a piece of data which was difficult (costly, time-consuming) to produce so as to satisfy certain requirements. It must be trivial to check whether data satisfies said requirements.
&lt;p&gt;Producing a proof of work can be a random process with low probability, so that a lot of trial and error is required on average before a valid proof of work is generated. Bitcoin uses the &lt;a href=&quot;/what-is-hashcash/&quot;&gt;hashcash&lt;/a&gt; proof of work.
&lt;p&gt;One application of this idea is using hashcash as a method to preventing email spam, requiring a proof of work on the email&amp;#39;s contents (including the To address), on every email.
&lt;p&gt;Legitimate emails will be able to do the work to generate the proof easily (not much work is required for a single email), but mass spam emailers will have difficulty generating the required proofs (which would require huge computational resources).
&lt;p&gt;Hashcash proofs of work are used in Bitcoin for block generation. Proofs of work that are tied to the data of each block are required for the blocks to be accepted. The difficulty of this work is adjusted so as to limit the rate at which new blocks can be generated by the network to one every 10 minutes.
&lt;p&gt;Due to the very low probability of successful generation, this makes it unpredictable which worker computer in the network will be able to generate the next block.
&lt;p&gt;For a block to be valid it must hash to a value less than the current target; this means that each block indicates that work has been done generating it. Each block contains the hash of the preceding block, thus each block has a chain of blocks that together contain a large amount of work.
&lt;p&gt;Changing a block (which can only be done by making a new block containing the same predecessor) requires regenerating all successors and redoing the work they contain. This protects the block chain from tampering.
&lt;p&gt;The most widely used proof-of-work scheme is SHA-256, which was introduced by Bitcoin. Some other hashing algorithms that are used for proof-of-work include scrypt, Blake-256, CryptoNight, HEFTY1, Quark, SHA-3, scrypt-jane, scrypt-n and combinations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-proof-of-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-proof-of-work/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Hashcash?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin uses the hashcash &lt;a href=&quot;/what-is-proof-of-work/&quot;&gt;Proof of Work&lt;/a&gt; function as the Bitcoin mining core. All bitcoin miners whether CPU, GPU, FPGA or ASICs are expending their effort creating hashcash proofs-of-work which act as a vote in the blockchain evolution and validate the blockchain transaction log.
&lt;p&gt;Like many cryptographic algorithms hashcash uses a hash function as a building block, in the same way that HMAC, or RSA signatures are defined on a pluggable hash-function (commonly denoted by the naming convention of algorithm-hash: HMAC-SHA1, HMAC-MD5, HMAC-SHA256, RSA-SHA1, etc), hashcash can be instantiated with different functions, hashcash-SHA1 (original), hashcash-SHA256^2 (bitcoin), hashcash-Scrypt(iter=1) (litecoin).
&lt;h3&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hashcash proof-of-work function was invented in 1997 by &lt;a href=&quot;http://cypherspace.org/adam/&quot;&gt;Dr. Adam Back&lt;/a&gt;, and proposed for anti-DoS uses including preventing: anonymous remailer and mail2news gateway abuse, nym name squatting on nymservers (replyable pseudonymous remailer severs), as well as general email anti-spam and general network abuse throttling.
&lt;p&gt;Before bitcoin, hashcash was used by SpamAssasin, and (with an incompatible format) by Microsoft (with the name &amp;quot;email postmark&amp;quot;) in hotmail, exchange, outlook etc and by i2p anonymity network, mixmaster anonymous remailer components and other systems.
&lt;p&gt;Hashcash was also used by Hal Finney&amp;#39;s bitcoin precursor RPOW as a way to mine coins. Wei Dai&amp;#39;s B-money Proposal, and Nick Szabo&amp;#39;s similar BitGold proposal bitcoin precursors, also were proposed in the context of hashcash mining.
&lt;h3&gt;Hash function choices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the original 1997 algorithm hashcash used SHA1 because at that time, this was the defacto and NIST recommended hash, and the previous defacto hash MD5 had recently started to show signs of weakness. Bitcoin being specified/released in 2008/2009 uses SHA256. There is actually no strong reason SHA1 would not have worked also, hashcash relies only on the hash partial preimage resistance property (security up to hash-size, 160-bit with SHA1) and not birthday collision hardness (security up to 80-bit), so the SHA1 hash is big enough.
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is anyway built to 128-bit security because 256-bit ECDSA is used, which also offers 128-bit security. Never the less SHA256 is the correct and more conservative choice because even SHA1 has started to show some weakenesses, though only in birthday collision, not in 2nd-preimage.
&lt;h3&gt;Double Hash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is using two hash iterations (denoted SHA256^2 ie &amp;quot;SHA256 function squared&amp;quot;) and the reason for this relates to a partial attack on the smaller but related SHA1 hash. SHA1&amp;#39;s resistance to birthday attacks has been partially broken as of 2005 in O(2^64) vs the design O(2^80). While hashcash relies on pre-image resistance and so is not vulnerable to birthday attacks, a generic method of hardening SHA1 against the birthday collision attack is to iterate it twice.
&lt;p&gt;A comparable attack on SHA256 does not exist so far, however as the design of SHA256 is similar to SHA1 it is probably defensive for applications to use double SHA256. And this is what bitcoin does, it is not necessary given hashcash reliance on preimage security, but it is a defensive step against future cryptanalytic developments. The attack on SHA1 and in principle other hashes of similar design like SHA256, was also the motivation for the NIST SHA3 design competition which is still ongoing.
&lt;h3&gt;Future Hash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the NIST SHA3 contest has finalised, bitcoin might in the future consider adopting hashcash-SHA3 as a security upgrade (eg a single invocation of SHA3 vs a double invocation of SHA256). It seems clear from the SHA1 break, and SHA256 is a similar design, that there was previously a misunderstanding about the security of hash functions against birthday collisions, and SHA3 finalists all aim to fix that issue.
&lt;p&gt;One aspect of relevance for hashcash-SHA3 is that there is some debate within the NIST comments process on the proposal of weakening SHA3&amp;#39;s resistance to pre-image attacks down to 128-bit (vs the full hash size as with previous hashes). The motivation is a small performance gain, with the rationale that some hash-pluggable algorithms do not rely on full-length pre-image resistance. The proposal has met with significant negative feedback due to it creating a non-standard security assumption (compared to all previous hashes), and therefore it creates risk and all hash-pluggable algorithms (like HMAC, RSA, DSA, hashcash etc) would need to be re-examined on a case by case basis to see if SHA3 is safe to use with them; from the balance of the feedback it seems probable that NIST will accept the feedback and SHA3 will retain the full 256-bit pre-image resistance.
&lt;h3&gt;Cryptanalytic Risks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A practical issue with switching to hashcash-SHA3 is that it would invalidate all existing ASIC mining hardware, and so is a change that would unlikely to be made except in the face of security risk; there is no indication that SHA1 or SHA256, or SHA256^2 are vulnerable to pre-image attack so the motivation is missing absent new cryptanalytic developments. In addition even if SHA256^2 became easier due to cryptanalytic attack, and miners started using whatever the new algorithmic approach was, it does not necessarily matter as difficulty would just adapt to it. One likely side-effect however would be that it would introduce more memory or pre-computation tradeoffs which could make ASICs unprofitable, or give advantages to people with large resources to do the pre-computations. Pre-computation advantages would perhaps be enough motivation to replace the hash with SHA3.
&lt;p&gt;Anyway this is all speculation if and until any pre-image affecting cryptanalytic attacks are found on SHA256.
&lt;h3&gt;Hashcash function&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hashcash algorithm is relatively simple to understand. The idea builds on a security property of cryptographic hashes, that they are designed to be hard to invert (so-called one-way or pre-image resistant property). You can compute y from x cheaply y=H(x) but it&amp;#39;s very hard to find x given only y. A full hash inversion has a known computationally infeasible brute-force running time, being O(2^k) where k is the hash size eg SHA256, k=256, and if a pre-image was found anyone could very efficiently verify it by computing one hash, so there is a huge asymmetry in full pre-image mining (computationally infeasible) vs verification (a single hash invocation).
&lt;p&gt;A second hash pre-image means given one-preimage x of hash y where y=H(x), the task is to find another pre-image of hash y: x&amp;#39; so that y=H(x&amp;#39;). This is not to be confused with a birthday collision which is to find two values x, x&amp;#39; so that H(x)=H(x&amp;#39;), this can be done in much lower work O(sqrt(2^k))=O(2^(k/2)) because you can proceed by computing many H(x) values and storing them until you find a matching pair. It takes a lot of memory, but there are memory-time tradeoffs.
&lt;p&gt;Version 0 of hashcash protocol (1997) used a partial 2nd pre-image, however the later version 1 (2002) uses partial pre-images of a fairly chosen string, rather than digits of pi or something arbitrary, 0^k (ie all 0 string) is used for convenience, so the work is to find x such that H(x)=0. This is also equally fair and only requires one hash invocation to verify vs two with 2nd partial-pre-images. (This optimisation was proposed by Hal Finney &amp;amp; independently by Thomas Boschloo).
&lt;p&gt;To make the work easier the definition of a partial-pre-image is to find x such that H(x)/2^(n-k) = 0 where / is the integer quotient from division, n is the size of the hash output (n=256-bits for SHA256) and k is the work factor, ie, the first k bits of the hash output are 0 . So for example k=20 requires average 1 million tries. It is actually the output that partially matches, not the pre-image, so could perhaps more accurately called a pre-image with a partial output match, however partial pre-image effectively a short-hand for that.
&lt;h3&gt;Adding purpose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the partial-pre-image x from y=H(x) is random it is just a disconnected proof-of-work to no purpose, everyone can see you did do the work, but they don&amp;#39;t know why, so users could reuse the same work for different services. To make the proof-of-work be bound to a service, or purpose, the hash must include s, a service string so the work becomes to find H(s,c)/2^(n-k)=0. The miner varies counter c until this is true. The service string could be a web server domain name, a recipients email address, or in bitcoin a block of the bitcoin blockchain ledger.
&lt;p&gt;One additional problem is that if multiple people are mining, using the same service string, they must not start with the same x or they may end up with the same proof, and anyone looking at it will not honor a duplicated copy of the same work as it could have been copied without work, the first to present it will be rewarded, and others will find their work rejected. To avoid risking wasting work in this way, there needs to be a random starting point, and so the work becomes to find H(s,x,c)/2^(n-k) = 0 where x is random (eg 128-bits to make it statistically infeasible for two users to maliciously or accidentally start at the same point), and c is the counter being varied, and s is the service string.
&lt;p&gt;This is what hashcash version 1 and bitcoin does. In fact in bitcoin the service string is the coinbase and the coinbase includes the recipients reward address, as well as the transactions to validate in the block. Bitcoin actually does not include a random start point x, reusing the reward address as the randomization factor to avoid collisions for this random start point purpose, which saves 16-bytes of space in the coinbase. For privacy bitcoin expect the miner to use a different reward address on each successful block.
&lt;h3&gt;More Precise Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hashcash as originally proposed has work 2^k where k is an integer, this means difficulty can only be scaled in powers of 2, this is slightly simpler as you can see and fully measure the difficulty just by counting 0s in hex/binary and was adequate for prior uses. (A lot of hashcash design choices are motivated by simplicity).
&lt;p&gt;But because bitcoin needs more precise and dynamic control of work (to target 10-minute block interval accurately), it changes k to be a fractional (floating-point) so the work becomes to find H(s,x,c) &amp;lt; 2^(n-k) which is equivalent if k is an integer. Bitcoin defines target = 2^(n-k), so the work can be more simply written to find H(s,x,c) &amp;lt; target. Of course because of luck the block time actually has quite high variance, but the average is still more accurately targeted by the introduction of fractional k.
&lt;h3&gt;Work, difficulty &amp;amp; cryptographic security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hashcash expresses security margin in the standard cryptographic security terms O(2^k) where for comparison DES offers k=56-bits of security, ECDSA-256 offers k=128-bits of security, and because its widely used this log2 way of expressing work and security can also be useful for making security comparisons.
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin rate of work is called the network hashrate in GH/sec. As the target block interval is 10 minutes that can be converted to cryptographic security as log2(hashrate&lt;em&gt;600), so that of Nov 2013 hashrate is 4 petahash/sec and bitcoin&amp;#39;s hashcash-256^2 proofs-of-works are 62-bits (including +1 for double hash).
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin also defines a new notion of (relative) difficulty which is the work required so that at current network hashrate a block is expected to be found every 10 minutes. It is expressed relative to a minimum work unit of 2^32 iterations (approximately, technically minimum work is 0xFFFF0000 due to bitcoin implementation level details). Bitcoin difficulty is simple to approximately convert to log2 cryptographic security: k=log2(difficulty)+32 (or for high accuracy log2(difficulty&lt;/em&gt;0xFFFF0000)). Difficulty is related to the target simply as difficulty = target / 0xFFFF0000.
&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps easier to deal with high difficulties in log2 scale (a petahash/second is a 16 decimal digit number of hashes per second), and makes them comparable to other cryptographic security statements. For example the EFF &amp;quot;deepcrack&amp;quot; DES cracker project built a hardware brute force machine capable of breaking a DES key in 56 hours to make a political point that 56-bit DES was too weak in 1998 at a cost of $250,000 (plus volunteer design time). By comparison bitcoin network does 62-bits (including +1 for double hash) every 10-minutes and is 537,000 times more powerful than deepcrack, or could if it were focused on DES rather than SHA256 crack a DES key in 9 seconds to deepcracks 56 hours.
&lt;h3&gt;Miner privacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In principle a miner should therefore for privacy use a different reward-address for each block (and reset the counter to 0). Why Satoshi&amp;#39;s early mined bitcoins were potentially linked, was because while he changed the reward-addresss, he forgot to reset the counter after each successful mine, which is a bitcoin mining privacy bug. In fact with bitcoin the counter also should be obscured otherwise you would reveal your effort level, and if you have a lot of mining power that may imply who the coin belongs to. Bitcoin does this via the nonce and extra-nonce. Nonce starts at 0, but extra nonce is random.
&lt;p&gt;Together these form a randomized counter hiding the amount of effort that went into the proof, so no one can tell if it was a powerful but unlucky miner who worked hard, or a weak miner who was very lucky.
&lt;p&gt;Additionally with the introduction of mining pools, if the miner uses the same reward address for all users, which is what the current mining protocols do, then there is risk that users may redo work. To avoid users redoing work, miners hand out defined work for the users to do. However this creates an unnecessary communication round trip and in early protocol versions perhaps was a factor in the decision to have the pool send the actual block to mine, which means the miners are not validating their own blocks, which delegates validation authority, though not work, to the pool operator, reducing the security of the bitcoin network.
&lt;p&gt;The more recent mining protocol version allows the user to add their own block definition, but still unnecessarily incur round trips for handing out work allocation. Because the new pooled-mining protocol has a miner chosen extraNonce this acts as a random start factor so there is actually no need to talk to the pool for work allocation, a pool could have a static published address, and miners could just do work of whatever size they chose, and submit it to the pool as a UDP packet. (If privacy is required by the miner, it could use the public derivation method from BIP 32 to allow the node to tell the miner via an encrypted message with the mining work, which factor to multiply the static public key by.)
&lt;h3&gt;Scrypt proof-of-work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a misunderstanding to talk about the Scrypt proof-of-work. Scrypt is not intended as a proof-of-work function, but a stretched key-derivation function, and while it is by design expensive to compute with high iterations, it can not be used to make an efficiently publicly auditable proof-of-work, as verifying costs the same as creating.
&lt;p&gt;Hashcash with the internal hash function of Scrypt may be denoted hashcash-Scrypt(1). Scrypt, by Colin Percival, is a key-derivation function for converting user chosen passphrases into keys. It is salted (to prevent pre-computation/rainbow table attacks), and the hash is iterated many times to slow down passphrase grinding. Scrypt is similar in purpose to the defacto standard passphrase key-derivation function PBKDF2 (which uses HMAC-SHA1 internally).
&lt;p&gt;The differentiator and why people might choose Scrypt rather than PBDF2 is that Scrypt&amp;#39;s inner hash uses more memory so the GPU (or theoretical Scrypt ASIC/FPGA) advantage in password grinding is reduced compared to CPUs.
&lt;p&gt;This does not use the key-stretching feature of Scrypt so mining is not actually using Scrypt directly, but only the inner Scrypt hash (accessed by setting the iteration parameter to one iteration). So Scrypt&amp;#39;s key-stretching function is not being used at all to contribute to the hardness, unlike its normal use for key protection eg in deriving the encryption key from user passphrase to encrypt bitcoin wallets.
&lt;p&gt;The reason Scrypt&amp;#39;s key-stretching can not be used for mining is because that simultaneously makes it more expensive to verify by the same factor. This hashcash variant can be denoted hashcash-Scrypt(iter=1,mem=128KB) or shortened to hashcash-Scrypt(1). The other major scrypt parameter denotes the amount of memory used (usually 128kB).
&lt;h3&gt;Decentralization: hashcash-Scrypt vs hashcash-SHA256&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 128kB Scrypt memory footprint makes litecoin arguably less vulnerable to centralization of mining power arising from limited access to or ownership of ASIC equipment by users. It&amp;#39;s arguable and unclear, because there are counter arguments: that hashcash-SHA256^2 is very simple, so a skilled individual with his personal savings or a small Kickstarter project could design and put in an order with a chip-fabricator.
&lt;p&gt;This simplicity ensures that many people will do it and ASICs should become available. Conversely it is somewhat more difficult in comparison to make an hashcash-Scrypt(1) ASIC so perhaps litecoin will prove in the mid-term actually worse for centralization, if a well funded commercial entity corners the market by having faster, but proprietary, not available on the market, hashcash-Scrypt(1) ASICs that render litecoin GPU mining unprofitable.
&lt;p&gt;Note also a mitigating factor is that it is considered that hashcash-Scrypt(1) should offer less speed up from ASIC implementation vs GPUs than hashcash-SHA256^2. This is claimed because of the argument that the die area taken up by 128kB of RAM, which it might be thought must be dedicated to each Scrypt(1) core, would reduce the number of Scrypt(1) cores that fit per chip. Note however that Scrypt(1) is not actually securely memory-hard in that it makes no attempt to prevent time-memory tradeoffs, so it is actually possible to repeat the computation of internal rounds to reduce the memory requirement.
&lt;p&gt;In theory therefore it would be possible though more computation expensive to implement Scrypt(iter=1, mem=128kB) with minimal memory, just with more work. In hardware the time-memory tradeoff would be optimized to find the optimal amount of memory to use, and it is quite possible the optimal amount would be less than 128kB.
&lt;p&gt;Hashcash-Scrypt(1) also has a disadvantage relative to hashcash-SHA256^2 in that it is significantly slower to verify, as the verification cost of one iteration of Scrypt(mem=128kB) is far higher than a two SHA256 hashes. This makes validating the litecoin blockchain more CPU and memory intensive for all full nodes.
&lt;p&gt;Note however that the dominating CPU work of validation is the verification of the per transaction ECDSA signatures of the multiple transactions in a block. Even one ECDSA signature is slower than one Scrypt(1) verification which is done once per block, and there are many transactions (and so ECDSA signature verifications) to verify within a block.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-hashcash/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-hashcash/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Bitcoin Mining Difficulty</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;What is Bitcoin Mining Difficulty?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/what-is-bitcoin-mining-difficulty.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/what-is-bitcoin-mining-difficulty-high-resolution.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Visualize and Download High-Resolution Infographic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Computationally-Difficult Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin mining a block is difficult because the SHA-256 hash of a block&amp;#39;s header must be lower than or equal to the target in order for the block to be accepted by the network.
&lt;p&gt;This problem can be simplified for explanation purposes: The hash of a block must start with a certain number of zeros. The probability of calculating a hash that starts with many zeros is very low, therefore many attempts must be made. In order to generate a new hash each round, a nonce is incremented. This is based on the &lt;a href=&quot;/what-is-hashcash/&quot;&gt;hashcash&lt;/a&gt; function.
&lt;h3&gt;The Bitcoin Network Difficulty Metric&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bitcoin network difficulty is the measure of how difficult it is to find a new block compared to the easiest it can ever be. It is recalculated every 2016 blocks to a value such that the previous 2016 blocks would have been generated in exactly two weeks had everyone been mining at this difficulty. This will yield, on average, one block every ten minutes.
&lt;p&gt;As more miners join, the rate of block creation will go up. As the rate of block generation goes up, the difficulty rises to compensate which will push the rate of block creation back down. Any blocks released by malicious miners that do not meet the required difficulty target will simply be rejected by everyone on the network and thus will be worthless.
&lt;h3&gt;The Block Reward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a block is discovered, the discoverer may award themselves a certain number of bitcoins, which is agreed-upon by everyone in the network. Currently this bounty is 25 bitcoins; this value will halve every 210,000 blocks. See Controlled Currency Supply.
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the miner is awarded the fees paid by users sending transactions. The fee is an incentive for the miner to include the transaction in their block. In the future, as the number of new bitcoins miners are allowed to create in each block dwindles, the fees will make up a much more important percentage of mining income.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-bitcoin-mining-difficulty/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-bitcoin-mining-difficulty/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learn How To Mine Bitcoins</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to learn how to mine bitcoins? First, mining bitcoins is done via SHA256.
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/j7opj5-32hw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started mining bitcoins you could get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/1155ghsantminerbitcoinminer&quot;&gt;Antminer S5&lt;/a&gt; for about $500 or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/17thsspondooliesbitcoinminer&quot;&gt;Spondoolies Tech SP20&lt;/a&gt; for about $500.
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZEV3QFj19u8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about how to use the best Bitcoin mining pools.
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pvrVtCOGTWY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn how to buy bitcoins and trade it
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GzSPSK6cn8E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about Bitcoin cloud mining.
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bd1doftVUHg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn about how to use gift card websites using Bitcoin
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ibh0AnQuyyA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - Bitcoin For Beginners - Learn How To Mine Bitcoin ! - Part 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to my Bitcoin for Beginners Tutorial.  Now in this video tutorial I&amp;#39;m going to cover what Bitcoin is?  How to mine it and some tips and tricks that you can use to make more money mining Bitcoin.  I just want to start off by saying if you want to skip the tutorial everything that I&amp;#39;m going to talk about is in the video description and is labeled accordingly.  So, you can just click on the video description, download the mining software, click on the link to view a calculator and try and figure out how much money you&amp;#39;ll make per week or per month and you kind of just run with the stuff find your own.  But if you want to watch the tutorial let&amp;#39;s begin.
&lt;p&gt;
So, the first thing that I want to touch on is what Bitcoin is.  Bitcoin is a new online digital currency.  It&amp;#39;s been around since about 2009, but just recently has gained a lot of popularity.  And now today one Bitcoin is worth a $116.  Now you might be asking yourself well, I don&amp;#39;t understand why is a Bitcoin worth so much?  What is a Bitcoin?  Now a Bitcoin really isn&amp;#39;t anything.  It doesn&amp;#39;t represent anything other than a number.  Now you might be wondering well, how do I get a Bitcoin?  You can get a Bitcoin in a number of different ways.  You can exchange your local currency like U.S. dollars for example or you can allow your computer to mine.  And mining is a process essentially that just uses your computer to solve mathematical problems and you are rewarded when you solve these problems with a service fee.  And those service fees while small add up especially depending on how fast your computer is.  And now there are people out there that make hundreds and thousands of dollars mining Bitcoin.
&lt;p&gt;
So you might say well, I&amp;#39;ve heard that Bitcoin is a scam or I&amp;#39;ve heard that Bitcoin is a Ponzi scheme.  Well, not really.  Essentially what&amp;#39;s happening here is that we&amp;#39;re allowing the Bitcoin Network which is a Napster like peer to peer network to use our computer to process information.  And so, every time our computer is processing information it&amp;#39;s allowing the entire financial network to operate.  So, when people want to send and receive Bitcoins they need computers to process that information in order to make that transaction.  So, just to give you an example, like Bank of America or Chase or Wells Fargo all of these really big banks they have skyscraper upon skyscraper of buildings and computers and servers to allow their entire financial network to run.  So, Bitcoin harnesses the Internet and all of the computers on the Internet in order to process all of these transactions and that&amp;#39;s why it&amp;#39;s not a scam or a Ponzi scheme.  Now the price of a Bitcoin may be inflated and by the time you watch this video the price of a Bitcoin may be more than a $116 or less than $116.  So, let&amp;#39;s get started.
&lt;p&gt;
The first thing that I want to show you is the Bitcoin wallet.  Now I&amp;#39;ll provide the download link to download the Bitcoin wallet.  Go ahead and download and install the Bitcoin wallet.  I&amp;#39;ll open it up for you just to show you what it looks like.  It&amp;#39;s already running and here it is.  It&amp;#39;s a very, very simple program.  It doesn&amp;#39;t do much.  Here&amp;#39;s my overview, you can see I&amp;#39;ve received three transactions recently.  And so once you download the Bitcoin wallet and run it, it will attempt to sync with the entire network and you&amp;#39;ll see a little progress bar down here at the bottom and it will begin to sync.  Now go ahead, leave it alone, let it sync.  There&amp;#39;s nothing that we&amp;#39;re going to do with this right now but we need it for later in the video tutorial.  So, after we download the Bitcoin wallet we&amp;#39;re going to have to download a miner program.  Now there are a number of different mining programs out there, CG miner, BF miner.  These require a little bit more background knowledge and so I wouldn&amp;#39;t recommend them for the beginner.  So, go ahead and download GUI miner.  You can find the download link in this video’s description.  Once you download GUI miner run the miner and you will see something similar to this screen.  Now you probably won&amp;#39;t have all of these tabs but all we need to do is click on file, new miner, Open CL miner and we&amp;#39;re going to give this new miner a name.  So you can name this whatever you&amp;#39;d like.  I&amp;#39;ll call this test miner for beginners.  Great.  And that will show us a screen similar to this.  But we don&amp;#39;t have a user name, we don&amp;#39;t have a password and this server is the pool that we&amp;#39;re going to join.  And that brings me to my next point.
&lt;p&gt;
Well, what&amp;#39;s a pool?  Well, a pool is basically a collective pool, a collective network of computers that are all working together to solve blocks of information to receive Bitcoin.  Now there are a number of different pools out there.  This is a really good chart of the pools that are currently available, BTC Guild is the largest pool followed by I believe BitMinter and 50BTC which are -- looks like they&amp;#39;re equal at 16%.  I&amp;#39;m going to show you Slush&amp;#39;s pool.  And the reason why I&amp;#39;m going to show you Slush&amp;#39;s pool is because I&amp;#39;ve had really good success with Slush&amp;#39;s pool.  I&amp;#39;ve tried Eligius which just wasn&amp;#39;t working out for me.  I wasn&amp;#39;t really making much progress.  BTC Guild for some reason I was making zero progress.  I&amp;#39;m not sure if I had everything set up correctly.  BitMinter is pretty popular, Deepbit is popular, but I&amp;#39;m going to show you Slush pool.  So, the first thing that we need to do now is join a pool.  So, to join Slush pool we&amp;#39;re going to type in this website here mining.bitcoin.cz and that&amp;#39;ll bring you to just Slush&amp;#39;s pool’s main website.  We can click here to sign up.  It&amp;#39;s totally free.  All you need is an e-mail you create a password.  Once you create an account you&amp;#39;ll be brought to a screen right here.  Now you can see here, Bitcoin address.  That is something that we&amp;#39;re going to get from our wallet.
&lt;p&gt;
So, let&amp;#39;s go back to our Bitcoin wallet and let&amp;#39;s go click on receive coins and we&amp;#39;re going to click on new address and we&amp;#39;re going to give that new address a label.  So I&amp;#39;ll give that -- let&amp;#39;s see Slush Pool for Beginners Address.  So, once I do that you can see it pops up here in this list.  And what I want to do is right click, copy that address, the string of code right here and I&amp;#39;m just going to paste it right here, just going to paste that address there.  And so, we&amp;#39;re going to keep the send threshold at 0.01.  These are just some statistics that will show you basically where you&amp;#39;re at in mining.  We&amp;#39;re going to save these settings.  Now we need to create a worker.  So, we&amp;#39;ve already figured out how we&amp;#39;re going to get paid now we need to create a worker.  And this is kind of like a log in and password information.  So, we&amp;#39;re going to register a new worker and we&amp;#39;re going to give this worker a name.  It can be anything that you want.  I&amp;#39;ll just type in beginner.  I&amp;#39;m going to give it a password.  I suggest just something simple 123 will work.  Leave everything else the same, click on Save and you&amp;#39;ll see here that it will create your worker.  Now this is what we need to copy.  Copy, go back to our miner and now we&amp;#39;re going to paste the worker username.  See I&amp;#39;m under that miner that I just created.  I&amp;#39;m going to paste the username, the password was 123 and the server is the pool and so you can see there are a bunch of pools but I&amp;#39;m showing you Slush&amp;#39;s pool.  So, I&amp;#39;ll select Slush&amp;#39;s pool and next to Device, this is where we can see which device we&amp;#39;ll be using.  We have my Intel i7 processor and then we also have our graphics card processor.  You want to select your graphics card processor.  That&amp;#39;s about a hundred times faster than just your standard computer&amp;#39;s CPU.  CPU affinity, I&amp;#39;m just going to keep that at zero and all we need to do is click this button, boom, start mining.
&lt;p&gt;
Now we&amp;#39;re going to also click on View, show summary and that&amp;#39;s going to actually show us a nice little summary of all of the activity in our mining program and all of our workers that are mining.  So, you can see here test miner for beginners.  I have it mining.  The only reason why it&amp;#39;s only at 2.1 is because I&amp;#39;m already using all of my CPU power in my previous miners.  I am just going to stop that.  And so you can see here I&amp;#39;m mining at 131 megahashes per second.  And I&amp;#39;ve only started this up within the last five minutes.  I&amp;#39;m already up to a 110 shares that have been accepted.  And I have zero stales.  Now this number here, this column, what this represents is a count of the number of times that you were given a bit of information for your computer to solve.  And your computer solved it and sent in the answer and your answer was confirmed as correct and accepted and so you get a share under accepted.  Now if you have any numbers in this column under stale basically what that means is that you were given some information to solve.  You solved it, you sent it in, but you sent it in too late or you sent it in and it was wrong.  So you&amp;#39;ll have a number under this column and that won&amp;#39;t be counted towards your payouts.  So every time you get an accepted share you get paid.  Now that&amp;#39;s really all we need to do.  Now your computer is mining.  So, the next thing that you should do is let&amp;#39;s try and figure out how much money we&amp;#39;re going to make with this speed.  And so, how we do that is we use a calculator, a Bitcoin mining calculator.
&lt;p&gt;So I am going to take this number here 130 megahashes per second and I&amp;#39;m going to go to this Bitcoin calculator that I found that I like.  That is great.  So I&amp;#39;m also going to include this link in the video description.  Go ahead and click on it.  And this is a Bitcoin mining calculator.  It&amp;#39;s great.  So we can enter in our megahashes per second which is 130.  You&amp;#39;re probably going to have a different number, it may be higher it may be lower.  And this is where we&amp;#39;re going to enter how many watts our computer’s using.  So, I have an 800 or an 850 power supply in my computer now.  Whether my computer is using all that power or not is debatable.  I don&amp;#39;t think it is so you know I&amp;#39;ll just put 400, 425.  I&amp;#39;ll split the difference.  Oops! 425 at a 130 and your cost per kilowatt, now this is the cost of electricity where you live.  Now if you&amp;#39;re not sure where or if you&amp;#39;re not sure how much the cost per kilowatt is you can always google that.  So, let&amp;#39;s just say that it&amp;#39;s 12 cents per kilowatt.  Let&amp;#39;s just say I didn&amp;#39;t have to spend anything.  I&amp;#39;m just using my normal desktop computer and let&amp;#39;s just run this thing for a month.  Now today a Bitcoin is worth a $116.  We&amp;#39;ll keep the difficulty just whatever it says, because that will change.  In the difficulty percent per month, I&amp;#39;m actually just going to keep that at one.  And this is 25 which is correct and I&amp;#39;ll just click on calculator and let&amp;#39;s see how much I&amp;#39;ll make.  Well, it looks like here that in 24 hours I&amp;#39;m actually going to make 68 cents.  But it&amp;#39;s going to cost me a $1.22 in power.  So, that&amp;#39;s a net loss of 54 cents.  So, it looks like in 24 hours one month one year 30 days, one month I&amp;#39;m going to lose $16, because I&amp;#39;m going to have to pay $36 in electricity bill.  So, this will give you an idea if you&amp;#39;re going to make any money or not.
&lt;p&gt;
So, then the question is well, how -- what do I have to do in order to make money?  Well, the answer is your megahashes per second.  This number here needs to be higher, needs to be higher than the amount of money that you need to spend on electricity.  So you need to make more Bitcoin than it costs to run your computer.  So, let me just give you an example.  Some people are making 3000 megahashes per second which equates to 3 gigahashes.  So, 3000 megahashes per second.  Let&amp;#39;s just say and actually this number here is probably wrong.  My computer probably doesn&amp;#39;t take 425 watts.  Let&amp;#39;s -- but let&amp;#39;s for this example, let&amp;#39;s just keep 425 watts, 3000 megahashes per second and let&amp;#39;s say the cost of electricity is a little bit higher at say 0.18 per kilowatt hour.  Cost of hardware, let&amp;#39;s just say it costs me $500, maybe I had to buy a new graphics card.  Time frame 30 days.  I&amp;#39;m going to bump that up to 90, three months.  Keep all those settings the same, calculate.  So, you can see here that in 90 days, three months, after spending $500 I would have made $1239.  I mean that&amp;#39;s pretty good.  Now these numbers obviously will change depending on what your computer specs are, how much power you&amp;#39;ll be using, but that&amp;#39;ll give you just a general ballpark idea as to how much money you can make with your computer.
&lt;p&gt;
So, just to quickly answer any question that you might have, in order to get this number higher, this megahash per second we need a faster graphics card.  And so a really good website that I found is this one here.  It will basically compare all of the graphics cards that are out on the market today.  So, we can scroll down here a little bit.  And so it will give you AMD (ATI) Radeon graphics cards.  Here is the model number and it will tell you the megahashes.  So, you can kind of guesstimate what your megahash number will be based on which graphics card you have or which graphics card you want to purchase.  Now mind you, you can plug in more than one graphics card to your computer.  But in order to do that you need to make sure that you have enough power to do that.  So, let&amp;#39;s just say you had two 5970s running at 704 megahashes per second times two, that&amp;#39;s 1408, so we could go back to the calculator we could put in 1408.  I&amp;#39;ll just keep that at 425.  This is just all guessing right here.  I don&amp;#39;t know what your numbers will be.  But you can see here that in one year thousand, 494 in one month, I&amp;#39;m sorry, 90 days.  So just, these are just some resources for you to check out and kind of experiment with.  All in all after watching this video you should have been able to at least set up your wallet, set up your mining software, set up your worker and connect to a pool which then you would be able to start mining.  And you&amp;#39;d be able to figure out what your megahash per second rate is.  So that&amp;#39;s it.  That concludes the Bitcoin for Beginners Tutorial.  Let us know what your megahash per second is, let us know what you&amp;#39;re working with or if you have any questions leave that information in the comments section below.  Thank you so much for watching and good luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - BitCoin for Beginners - Mac OS Mining, Tips, Mining Software, Wallets And More !&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Bitcoin for Beginners Part 2.  Bitcoin is an online virtual currency that has increased in value by more than $200 a coin since I last released Part 1 of this video series.  A Bitcoin today is now worth over $300.  Okay.  This may change by the time you watch this video but I wanted to address some of the most common questions that I received in Part 1.  Let you know some of the alternatives for the Bitcoin wallet because a lot of people had some issues syncing to the network and getting that to work.  Also, I wanted to show you another mining program that you can try in case you&amp;#39;re having trouble with GUI miner.  You can see I am running GUI miner right here.  I also wanted to show you a miner that the Mac users can use.  So I&amp;#39;ll be going over that as well.  Everything that I&amp;#39;m going to cover will be in the video description so if you&amp;#39;d like to skip the video and play around with this stuff by all means go ahead.  If you&amp;#39;re staying let&amp;#39;s get started.
&lt;p&gt;
People were reporting that they were having issues with their Bitcoin wallet.  Either they were having issues running the program on their computer or that it was taking too long to sync and never fully syncing up to the Bitcoin network.  MultiBit is a popular Bitcoin wallet.  It&amp;#39;s going to work a little bit better on your system especially for the people that were unable to get the original Bitcoin wallet working.  Now, MultiBit works from Mac, PC and Linux so it covers everybody.  And one of the best things about it is that you can password protect your wallet.  Now I want to make a side note.  I was unable to export my wallet from Bitcoin QT and import it into MultiBit.  But that&amp;#39;s okay because we can just simply send ourselves the coins from this wallet to this wallet.  And I&amp;#39;m going to show you how to do that.  Here&amp;#39;s my old Bitcoin wallet.  This is the wallet that I showed in video number one.  Now to transfer money from this wallet to MultiBit, I&amp;#39;ll just copy this address and I will click on send coins and I&amp;#39;ll pay to and I&amp;#39;ll paste my address and I&amp;#39;ll give this a label and I&amp;#39;ll call it transfer.  And under the amount I&amp;#39;m going to take my entire balance which isn&amp;#39;t very much but nevertheless I&amp;#39;ll copy that and I&amp;#39;ll paste it there.  And this is going to be in Bitcoin.  And then I’ll click on the send button.  Are you sure you want to send to the following address?  Yes, okay.  We get a little notification down here, gives us the date, the amount, it&amp;#39;s a negative.  You can see sent to address transfer up and there it is right there.  It just transferred.  It&amp;#39;s actually worth $11 and 57 cents.  That&amp;#39;s awesome.  I did not know that.  So, that&amp;#39;s how you would transfer money from one wallet to another wallet.  And if we click on the transactions tab we can see the transaction, we can see all the information about it.  It basically just confirms that we transferred that amount of money.
&lt;p&gt;
Now that I transfer money from one wallet to another wallet I&amp;#39;m going to add a password to my wallet and I can do that very easily by just selecting file, add password and I can add a password.  I&amp;#39;m going to type this in twice.  See where it says keep your password safe you need this password to spend your Bitcoin and it cannot be recovered if lost.  So it&amp;#39;s very, very, very important that you do not lose this password.  You write it down and you save it because if you lose your password you&amp;#39;re most likely going to lose your money.  So now that I&amp;#39;ve put my password in both fields and to the same I can add password to wallet and the password was added successfully.  So now my wallet is password protected.  Moving forward, because a lot of people were having issues getting their miner program to work I&amp;#39;m going to show you an alternative mining program that will work for Mac and PC.  Now we have CG miner and Diablo miner.  They both work for Mac and PC but for some reason I was unable to get Diablo miner to work.  But the Mac guys I would suggest trying this anyways.  Now I&amp;#39;m going to show you CG miner.  It&amp;#39;s not as nice looking as GUI miner but look at the job done and it&amp;#39;s a great alternative if you can&amp;#39;t get GUI miner to work, especially if you&amp;#39;re on a Mac.  So here&amp;#39;s GUI miner.  It&amp;#39;s already running so this is what it looks like when it&amp;#39;s all set up and running.  So I&amp;#39;m going to show you how to set this up from scratch so I&amp;#39;ll close out of here and I&amp;#39;ll launch CG miner.  When CG miner launches it&amp;#39;s just this black command prompt window.  It&amp;#39;s pretty basic.  It might scare some people but it&amp;#39;s not that confusing.  So let&amp;#39;s get started.  Everything I&amp;#39;m going to show you with CG miner is going to have to do with Slush&amp;#39;s Pool because that&amp;#39;s the pool I&amp;#39;m in.  And that&amp;#39;s the pool that I showed you how to set up in the previous video.
&lt;p&gt;
So it&amp;#39;s asking us for a URL and the URL for Slush&amp;#39;s Pool is the following stratum.bitcoin.cz:3333.  We just click on enter and it&amp;#39;s going to ask us for a username.  Now, it&amp;#39;s not asking us for the username to log in.  It&amp;#39;s asking us for the worker log in and password so I&amp;#39;ve already logged into my account here at mining.bitcoin.cz.  I&amp;#39;ve already created my workers and I&amp;#39;m going to type in this information for the username.  And I want to make a quick side note.  This is case sensitive so see how this is a capital H and a capital R.  It&amp;#39;s very important that I do capital H, capital R.  Click on enter.  It&amp;#39;s going to ask me for a password.  I&amp;#39;ll just put in this 123 password and click on enter.  Now it&amp;#39;s going to take just a second for this whole thing to get going but you can see that it&amp;#39;s working and there it is.  Now our miner is up and running and you can see that we have some information displayed here and it&amp;#39;s just a little difficult to see but it is all here.  So we can see our GPU, we can see what our megahash or kilohash per second is.
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I already have GUI miner running so this isn&amp;#39;t really going to do much for me.  You&amp;#39;re probably wondering well how this doesn&amp;#39;t really look like anything how do I keep track of anything?  Well, you can see here that we have some information that will just thread up for us and what we really want to do is go over here to our account and this is where we&amp;#39;re going to keep track of all of our workers, what they&amp;#39;re doing?  What the megahash per second is, just everything about our workers and then of course all of our Bitcoin information as far as where we want our Bitcoins to be deposited, when they will be sent, how much Bitcoin I need to accumulate before they&amp;#39;re sent to my Bitcoin wallet.  So I really should change this to like 0.00001.  That way I just get things sent to my wallet.  Oh, looks like it’s point 0.01.  So, set that back to 0.01.  And yes, so this is where you&amp;#39;re going to keep track of your status and basically your progress and how far along you are at mining.  So, this little program right here CG miner, that&amp;#39;s how you get it going on Slush&amp;#39;s Pool and this can now just be running in the background of your computer and you can just forget about it.
&lt;p&gt;So, that&amp;#39;s how you set up CG miner.  And like I said it works for Mac and PC.  Now, of course, I highly recommend GUI miner.  I think this program is awesome.  It works great.  It&amp;#39;s so easy to set up and I showed you how to set it up in Part 1.  So if you can use this definitely use GUI miner.
&lt;p&gt;So, that wraps up Part 2 of the Bitcoin for Beginners video series.  In Part 3, I&amp;#39;ll be going over pools in a little bit more detail.  We&amp;#39;ll talk about which pool you should join and why?  We&amp;#39;ll also take a look at the Bitcoin market and where the currency may be headed in the coming months, years.  I&amp;#39;ll also show you how to exchange your Bitcoin into cold hard cash because that&amp;#39;s something that a lot of people we&amp;#39;re requesting for.  So, with that being said thanks for watching and I&amp;#39;ll see you in Part 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - BitCoin For Beginners - POOLS - Top 3 Mining Pools - Trading and Exchanging - Part 3 1/2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Part 3 of the Bitcoin for Beginners video series.  If you&amp;#39;ve made it this far, you&amp;#39;ve probably started mining already.  In this part, I&amp;#39;ll be covering multiple topics, pools, and more specifically which pool you should join and why.  It&amp;#39;s never too late to switch and I encourage you to try different pools to see which work best for you.  The Bitcoin market, where it may be headed in the future and how we can capitalize on trading this currency.  Lastly, we&amp;#39;ll cover how to exchange your Bitcoin for cash, so we can cash out into real U.S. dollars to buy goods or services.  I’ll also quickly mention how you can spend your Bitcoin as well.
&lt;p&gt;
Now I must say that I have no personal affiliation with any of these pools and everything that I&amp;#39;m going to cover will be in the video description like always.  So feel free to check it out.  Okay, ready?  Let&amp;#39;s get started.
&lt;p&gt;
So, which pool should you join and why.  Choosing a pool that works for you and your hardware setup is important because it will ultimately determine how much Bitcoin you&amp;#39;ll make.  Each pool has a different payout structure and pool fees associated with it.  And this should be considered when choosing a pool.  First, let&amp;#39;s take a look at what pools are currently available to join and what market share they have.
&lt;p&gt;
Here&amp;#39;s a nice visual pie chart showing each pool and their size compared to one another.  BTC Guild, clearly the largest pool and one of the original pools first created for Bitcoin.  There are advantages and disadvantages to joining such a large pool and we&amp;#39;ll cover those in more detail in just a moment.  But the biggest thing to consider with a pool of this size is the competition within it.  Since the pool is so large it can affect your luck or likelihood of you sending incorrect information and receiving of award.  While this may just be speculation, I believe pool size is related to accepted answers versus stale answers which don&amp;#39;t count.  To elaborate further, pool size will also determine pool speed which determines how fast blocks are found and solved within the Bitcoin network.
&lt;p&gt;
Moving forward, GHash.IO, this is not a public pool that anyone can join.  Instead, it&amp;#39;s an exchange, kind of like a stock exchange.  But instead of stocks, you&amp;#39;re buying mining power, instead of a physical mining rig and joining a pool with it.  So the goal of this method is to reap the benefits of what that power can mine in the Bitcoin market.  Their units of measure for mining power is gigahash per second, which is a thousand megahashes per second.  So they provide the power and you sit back and collect the profits.  Well, this may sound attractive.  I&amp;#39;d be wary of anything claiming to make you rich with very little effort.  Of course, they take a percentage.  And word on the street is that the return on investment doesn&amp;#39;t match up with what the return would be if you owned the rig producing that amount of power.  But for the reason that it&amp;#39;s not available to join freely, this pool is out.
&lt;p&gt;
Next is Eligius.  This is a free no registration public pool that anyone can join.  Simply point your miners to Eligius’ URL: stratum.mining.eligius.st:3334 and you can connect and start mining immediately.  Typically, you need to register an account with most pools and create workers to manage your mining and your statistics.  The developer of this pool, Wizkid, is doing a great job and I know a lot of people appreciate the hard work he&amp;#39;s putting in to maintaining this pool’s profitability.
&lt;p&gt;
At 7%, BitMinter is the fourth largest pool available.  Now registration is easy and they even provide their own mining clients for you to use, which is cool.  No one else is doing that from what I&amp;#39;m seeing.  And this can be a huge advantage for a beginner just starting out, doesn&amp;#39;t really want to learn how to get these miners to work.  You could just use their miner.  However, their client is coded in Java, which may not be preferred by more advanced users but you can point any mining client to their pool.  So it really makes no difference.  I don&amp;#39;t have much experience with this pool, but I really like their setup and support.
&lt;p&gt;
Slush&amp;#39;s pool, coming in fifth, is six percent of the total mining market just behind BitMinter.  Now this is the pool that I have been involved with and I&amp;#39;ve had great success mining it.  I haven&amp;#39;t found a pool that pays more frequently and as much as Slush&amp;#39;s pool.  But this I cannot explain.  Everyone will have a different experience with each pool and Slush&amp;#39;s may not work well for someone else.  To be honest, it works for me.  I like the guy who&amp;#39;s running it and I believe he&amp;#39;s genuinely trying to offer the best pool option out there.  Personally, I believe my success is somewhat related to the fact that I&amp;#39;m not in the largest pool.  Rather, I&amp;#39;m in a somewhat smaller pool where opportunity is greater for the individual.  It&amp;#39;s also very basic and simple, no strings attached.  And for this reason I&amp;#39;m putting Slush&amp;#39;s pool as my number-one pick.  Number two will be BitMinter and Eligius will round out the top three.
&lt;p&gt;
A lot of people are wondering what the unknown pool is.  This is not any specific pool, it&amp;#39;s the amount of people that are mining on their own or have started private pools that we cannot join unless we&amp;#39;re invited to.  Now, these private pools make up a whopping 12% of the total market and is needed in the overall picture to keep all of the other pools in check.  If any pool gets too large, there&amp;#39;s a risk that they will quote, &amp;quot;Run away with the market.&amp;quot;  Some say this could happen if any pool reaches 50% of market share.  But there’ll always be people who don&amp;#39;t want any affiliation with any pool and will mine on their own.  But more pools create more competition between them, which in turn, is beneficial for the miners like us.
&lt;p&gt;
Then we have these smaller individual pools.  And these smaller pools here are also available options.  However, I hate to say it, but there&amp;#39;s usually a reason why they haven&amp;#39;t caught on.  Yes, maybe some are just starting up and take a while to build up a user base but they move slower and find blocks slower, maybe too slow.  Let&amp;#39;s just take a look at Deepbit for example.  This pool may only be 2% in size because they charge a 10% pool fee.  So, I&amp;#39;m not too interested in these smaller pools right now.  But speaking of fees, let&amp;#39;s take a look at a chart I found for pool fees.  This is a great resource and I will also be linking to it in the video description along with everything else that I&amp;#39;m talking about.  Now at the top here, we have our reward types and explanations.  And if we scroll down just a bit we see a nice chart outlining pool fees and payout structures as well as other useful pool information.
&lt;p&gt;
Now you can see here is BTC Guild.  If you remember, this was the largest pool in that pie chart.  Under transaction fees, we can see that they are shared, but more specifically shared on a PPLNSG basis.  Now they have a 5% pay per share fee and a 3% other fee, which totals their fees at 8%.  Now let&amp;#39;s look at BitMinter.  BitMinter is also shared but only has a 1% fee.  Slush&amp;#39;s pool here is shared but has a 2% fee.  Naturally, you might think immediately, &amp;quot;Well, I want to join the pool with the lowest overall pool fee.&amp;quot;  But because each pool will produce different results, it&amp;#39;s absolutely possible that a pool with a lower fee performs more poorly overall compared to a pool with a slightly higher fee.  So, if we scroll down a little bit more, we can see Eligius.  Okay.  They also have a shared transaction fee, 0% pay per share fee but it&amp;#39;s blank under other fees and I can only imagine that they must charge some kind of fee just to cover their overhead, which is totally understandable and normal and okay in my book.  But if you look at some of these other statistics for these other pools, some of them are charging as much as 10% in pay per share fees and don&amp;#39;t even share the transaction fee.  They are kept by the pool.  So, if you&amp;#39;re choosing a pool for the long haul, this is really something you should consider.
&lt;p&gt;
That concludes the first half of Part 3.  In the next half, we&amp;#39;ll cover the Bitcoin market and how much the price of a Bitcoin may reach, how we can capitalize on that.  And then, of course, how we&amp;#39;re going to cash out our Bitcoins for U.S. dollars because that&amp;#39;s something that everyone has been asking for.  So, please, click here to continue on to the second half of Part 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - BitCoin For Beginners - How To Buy BitCoin And Trade It - Part 3 2/2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the second half of Part 3 in the Bitcoin for Beginners video series.  Now first I want to quickly say thank you to all the people who have been watching these videos since Part 1.  And then of course the newcomers who may be joining us and watching this video for the first time today.
&lt;p&gt;
Hello.  I&amp;#39;ve received a lot of great feedback, questions and comments.  One comment I see often is people asking for Bitcoin.  So I&amp;#39;m going to be giving away $60 worth of Bitcoin to four people.  Anyone can join and I&amp;#39;m looking forward to announcing the winners in this video&amp;#39;s description and in Part 4.  I&amp;#39;ll then be doing another contest in Part 4 in case you missed this one.  So, be sure to subscribe and watch the rest of this video because I&amp;#39;m going to tell you how you can win, but first here we go with the second half of Part 3 in the Bitcoin for Beginners video series.
&lt;p&gt;
We left off talking about mining pools in the first half.  Now let&amp;#39;s take a look at the market price of Bitcoin and how we can capitalize on that.  On Thursday, November 28, 2013 the price of one Bitcoin finally reached over a $1000 per coin.  Now whether it will continue to rise or drop significantly tomorrow is uncertain.  But I think there is still room for this price to grow.  $2000 per coin doesn&amp;#39;t sound as crazy as it might have just a few months ago.  Well, I&amp;#39;m not here to make predictions I&amp;#39;m just trying to point out the opportunity we&amp;#39;re all faced with today while realizing the risks of tomorrow on the morning of the 28th and you can see it continued to spike up.  We went as high as 1200 and then we dipped, had a spike and it looks like we may be coming back for another return to that 1200, 1250 and beyond.  Now how do we capitalize on all this money that&amp;#39;s being made with Bitcoin?  How can we make some money and get a slice of the pie?  How can we exchange our Bitcoin for real money?  I&amp;#39;m going to show you a few ways we can take advantage of Bitcoin including trading the currency, cloud mining and buying stuff with Bitcoin.  Now we can mine Bitcoin with our computers like I&amp;#39;ve been showing you how to do in the previous parts or we can trade the currency like a stock in the stock market.  I&amp;#39;m going to refer to this as buying and selling or investing.  So let&amp;#39;s simplify this.
&lt;p&gt;
If we can acquire Bitcoin at price X, let&amp;#39;s just say a $1000 which is roughly today&amp;#39;s market price, and then sell that Bitcoin if it reaches price Y, let&amp;#39;s just say $1100.  So, in this scenario we would make $100 per coin or lose $100 per coin if you reverse the numbers.  I know the first thing you&amp;#39;re thinking is “well, wait I don&amp;#39;t have a $1000 to risk losing gambling on Bitcoin”.  And I’d say you don&amp;#39;t need a $1000 that&amp;#39;s just the price of one Bitcoin today.  You can purchase half a Bitcoin or .3, .2.  For example, maybe you have a $100 from your recent paycheck and you want to invest only $100 into Bitcoin.  Then you would purchase only .1 Bitcoins.  The point I&amp;#39;m trying to make here is that you can still make money with smaller investments in Bitcoin.  So make sure to invest with what you&amp;#39;re willing to lose or at least lose 50% of.  That leads us to the next question.  How do I buy only a $100 worth of Bitcoin? Or if you already have Bitcoin and you just need to sell it or exchange it I&amp;#39;ll get to that in just a moment.  But we first need to purchase a $100 worth of Bitcoin so we can sell it later at a higher price and make a profit and we can do that using Coinbase.
&lt;p&gt;
Now I&amp;#39;ve showed Coinbase before.  Coinbase is one of the largest and most trusted sources for buying and selling and for protecting our Bitcoin, let&amp;#39;s just say, from hackers.  I&amp;#39;ve already created an account with Coinbase and I&amp;#39;m already logged in you can see that here.  Now if you already have Bitcoin and all you need to do is send it to your Coinbase account you can click on account settings and then you can click on Bitcoin addresses and you can create a new Bitcoin address.  Send all of your coins to Coinbase.  Now you’ll also need to connect a bank account and you can do that by clicking on Buy/Sell and clicking on limits and verifications.  I&amp;#39;ve already done that and so now we&amp;#39;re going to click on Buy/Sell and we can enter the amount that we want to buy and we can just enter in 1, but if we enter in 1 that&amp;#39;s a $1000 that&amp;#39;s the price of a Bitcoin today.  But what we want to do for this example is only buy a $100 worth of Bitcoin.  So we&amp;#39;ll enter in .1.  That’ll change these numbers down here.  You can see that my payment method is the bank account that I&amp;#39;ve already linked.  You can see that .1 today equals just over $100.  If we needed to get it to a $100 perfectly we might have to go .098 possibly.  That&amp;#39;s close maybe .097 but we&amp;#39;re just going to round as close as we can so a $101.50 is close enough.  And all we need to do is enter that amount here.  We&amp;#39;ll click on buy Bitcoin, that&amp;#39;ll bring up this splash screen.  So, I&amp;#39;ll just quickly click on confirm and that&amp;#39;s all I need to do.  We have now bought a $100 worth of Bitcoin.  I can now sell this $100 worth of Bitcoin if the price goes up and realize a profit.  It&amp;#39;s that simple.
&lt;p&gt;
Now, for those of you who want to participate in my free Bitcoin giveaway contest, here&amp;#39;s how to play.  Step one, leave me your usual comments or questions or spam but be sure to ask for your share link.  When you ask me for a share link I will then reply to your comment with the link that you&amp;#39;ll need to use to share this video.  If you do not use the link that I give you, you cannot win.  Step two, take the link I give you from your comment and post it on your Facebook, Twitter, Google plus, LinkedIn or wherever you want to share it.  The top four people with the most followed link will receive $15 in Bitcoin.  I will send you the coin in two weeks to any address that you specify when the contest is over.  The contest will end December 17th, 2013.  So, this will be a lot of fun and you&amp;#39;ll be able to take what you&amp;#39;ve learned in my videos and apply it in real life with your own Bitcoin.  Anyone can enter and anyone can win.  If nobody asks for a share link in the comment section below it&amp;#39;s going to be extremely easy for the top four people to win.  So make sure you comment.
&lt;p&gt;
So, like I said I&amp;#39;m really looking forward to giving back to you guys.  You guys are awesome.  We&amp;#39;re going to keep going with this and I&amp;#39;ll be announcing the winners in this video’s description and in Part 4 when we do another $60 Bitcoin giveaway contest just in case you missed this one.
&lt;p&gt;
So, in Part 4 I&amp;#39;m going to go over cloud mining in a little bit more detail where we can do that.  I&amp;#39;m also going to show you how we can do some online shopping with Bitcoin to buy things, especially like I&amp;#39;ve been saying gift cards, because people have been asking for that.  So make sure to subscribe and I&amp;#39;ll be seeing you in Part 4.  Good luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - BitCoin For Beginners - Cloud Mining &amp;amp; Cloud Hashing - Part 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to Bitcoin for Beginners Part 4.  Now, we left off in the second half of Part 3 talking about the market price of Bitcoin and some of the ways we can buy and sell this virtual asset.  In Part 4, we&amp;#39;re going to talk about Cloud Mining.  What it is, where we can do it and then my final review of whether it&amp;#39;s profitable or not.  But before we get started we have to announce the winners of last week&amp;#39;s free Bitcoin giveaway contest.  I want to first thank everyone for participating.  So many people entered the contest it was unbelievable and it was so much fun interacting with all of you.  Like I said before this will be a great opportunity for you to apply what you&amp;#39;ve learned in these videos with your very own Bitcoin.  So, the contest involved the share link which I had asked you to use when re-sharing this video.  The results are in and it is now time to announce the four winners that will each receive $15 in Bitcoin.
&lt;p&gt;And the winners are Soulragepage, tusingresosxinternet, Kris P and there’s a tie for fourth place between Ernesto Del Frade and Alexander Parsan.  Congratulations everyone and thank you for participating.  If you missed out on this contest we&amp;#39;re having a free Bitcoin giveaway contest Round 2 in this video.  But instead of share links this time we&amp;#39;re going to do something a little different that I think will be more fun and interactive for everyone and like always anyone can enter and anyone can win.  But before I get into the video contest details let&amp;#39;s get started with Part 4 of the Bitcoin for Beginners video series.
&lt;p&gt;
Cloud Mining or Cloud Hashing.  What is it?  Where can we do this?  Does it make sense to even do it?  These are all great questions and they actually came from you guys.  Now some people can’t afford to buy their own mining equipment, especially when it can cost hundreds or thousands of dollars or maybe they just don&amp;#39;t know how to run the equipment properly for one reason or another.  So Cloud Mining is essentially buying the power or the hashing speed that a mining rig generates.  So you&amp;#39;re not actually buying the physical computer and the parts and the components.  You&amp;#39;re buying a portion of the speed that the mining rig is mining at.&lt;p&gt;  Think of it as a car.  A car can go a 100 miles per hour but it&amp;#39;s going to cost you $20 to go one mile per hour and therefore $40 to go two miles per hour.  Now with a car you&amp;#39;d be paying for the distance it can carry you.  But with Cloud Mining you&amp;#39;re paying for the speed at which you can mine Bitcoin at.  The more speed you buy the further you can go or the more Bitcoin you can make.&lt;p&gt;  Now let&amp;#39;s apply this to a mining rig.  Let&amp;#39;s just say I have a super mining rig and you want to cloud mine with me.  I&amp;#39;ve decided to offer mining speed to you at one gigahash for $20.  So you can pay me $20 to have my machine mine Bitcoin for you at the speed of one gigahash per second.  Now that&amp;#39;s yours and whatever profits it makes is yours to keep.  So that sounds pretty good.  You don&amp;#39;t have to pay for any of the equipment but you&amp;#39;re now mining Bitcoin at one gigahash per second using the cloud.  However, a car needs gas to keep moving and a mining rig needs power to keep mining.  So, instead of only paying me $20 once for the one gigahash per second we will enter into a contract together.  Like a cell phone contract, which you will have to renew on a yearly basis or however long I decided to be.
&lt;p&gt;
Now my contract basically says that I&amp;#39;m letting you borrow one gigahash per second mining speed from me on a yearly basis.  So that means you will need to renew this contract and pay me $20 a year to have my machine mine for you at the speed of one gigahash second.  Now, not all cloud mining companies are like this.  Some allow you to buy the mining speed for a onetime payment and some offer smaller monthly payments.  After you purchase the contract from me and you agree to my terms, my machine will start mining for you and you can sit back and collect the Bitcoin it mines.  This is called Cloud Mining or Cloud Hashing.  Let&amp;#39;s quickly take a look at some of the popular cloud mining companies that we can choose from.  Now the first one that I&amp;#39;m going to show you, and these are in no particular order, is cloudhashing.com. &lt;p&gt; Now if we go to cloudhashing.com, we can just click on personal contracts and we can see the contracts that they are offering us.  Now they have a silver, gold and platinum contract.  Now their silver contract is a one-year contract.  Their gold and platinum contracts are two-year contracts.  Now let&amp;#39;s just take a look at this silver contract.  The silver contract is for four Gigahashes per second.  And it&amp;#39;s a one-year contract.  Now this is for $275 that we need to pay them upfront.  Now if we do the math on that $275 divided by 12 months is $22 a month.  But we&amp;#39;re getting four gigahashes so divided by four they&amp;#39;re charging us five dollars per gigahash.  So, these are the numbers that we would want to really make sure we understand before we get involved with Cloud Mining and Cloud Hashing.
&lt;p&gt;
The next company I want to show you is minercloud.com.  Now we can just go to minercloud.com and we can scroll down on their main page to see which contracts they offer and for how much.  Now just like cloudhashing.com, minercloud has three contracts as well.  They have an $89 per year, a $139 per year and a $329 per year.  And we can see how many gigahashes per second they&amp;#39;re offering for each price.  Just like we did before, we can do the math again.  So here&amp;#39;s my calculator and I can do $89 a year divided by 12 months.  That&amp;#39;s $7 a month for one gigahash per second.  Now it&amp;#39;s just a few dollars more than the previous company I showed you which was five, but this is a smaller upfront cost.  It&amp;#39;s only $89 and we could order multiple contracts.&lt;p&gt;  CEX.IO is by far the most popular cloud mining platform out there.  Now if we look at the Bitcoin hashrate distribution GHash.IO, which is CEX.IO’s pool, we can see that they have 20% of the total mining market.  So they&amp;#39;re really big.  Now CEX.IO works very similarly to the other companies I just showed you.  They offer contracts and they offer contracts by the gigahash per second.  So their prices are a little bit higher.  Now we can see it, they&amp;#39;re offering their gigahashes at .07 Bitcoins, but how much is that in U.S. dollars?  Well, today I can just go over to Coinbase and type in .07 which is equivalent to $48.  So they&amp;#39;re charging $48 a gigahash whereas these other companies are offering gigahashes at $5 and $7.
&lt;p&gt;
Now this company CEX.IO does allow you to buy and sell these contracts and you can terminate the contract at any time.  So they do offer you some added flexibility.  Another benefit of CEX.IO is they don&amp;#39;t only mine Bitcoin for you, you can cloud mine other types of virtual assets.  CEX.IO is more expensive but they have a calculator that will allow us to estimate our mining profit.  So let&amp;#39;s take a look at that.  So here&amp;#39;s the CEX.IO estimate your mining profit calculator.  On the left hand side we can put in our parameters and on the right hand side we can see our payout schedule and our monthly profit.  Now these numbers can be confusing and let&amp;#39;s go through them one at a time.  Hashrate, this is the amount of gigahashes per second that we&amp;#39;re going to purchase.
&lt;p&gt;Now remember on CEX.IO right now each gigahash is worth $48.  So, that&amp;#39;s pretty expensive so let&amp;#39;s only purchase one gigahash per second for $48.  Maintenance fee and pool fee is at 3%.  Those are reasonable numbers we&amp;#39;re going to keep them at 3%.  Now network stats, current difficulty.  The current difficulty is 908.35, they&amp;#39;ve just rounded some decibels, but the difficulty increase per month isn&amp;#39;t going to be as high as 50.  Now remember the higher the difficulty increase per month the less amount of coins that we&amp;#39;re going to make.  So we can just quickly look back at the difficulty history and see what the difficulty increase percentage has been for the last few months.  And we can see that it&amp;#39;s been fluctuating between 20, 29, 32, 41, 46, 30, 16, 28.  So I think a reasonable number to put in here would be 35%.
&lt;p&gt;
Now under conversion, the conversion rate right now is not $142 for one Bitcoin, 681 for the price of one Bitcoin.  Now the conversion increase per month is asking us what percent increase is Bitcoin going to be worth each and every month.  So let&amp;#39;s just leave this at zero because anything positive in this box here will be just better for us.  So let&amp;#39;s assume that the price of Bitcoin is going to stay at 681.  We&amp;#39;ll click on calculate and we can see now we have our numbers in the right hand side for the mining payout schedule.  So under monthly profit we can see that the first month we&amp;#39;re going to make  .02 Bitcoins, then .01, then .01, .01 but by the fifth month we&amp;#39;re not going to make any more Bitcoin.  You can see that we no longer will make Bitcoin after five months by only purchasing one gigahash per second.  So, let&amp;#39;s first figure out how much .04 Bitcoin is today if the price does not increase.  Let’s go to Coinbase put in .04.  Now, .04 is only worth $28 but it cost us $48 to buy one gigahash per second.  So in five months we haven&amp;#39;t even been able to make our money back let alone make some profit.
&lt;p&gt;So this is one of the reasons why I&amp;#39;m not a big fan of cloud mining because you would have to keep purchasing gigahashes every month or however quickly you want in order to try and make your money back, but you&amp;#39;ll never actually get the money back.  Now this may be because CEX.IO charges so much money per gigahash and it might be profitable if the gigahash per second that they&amp;#39;re selling wasn&amp;#39;t $48 and was only $10.  Now this is one of the reasons why I have decided not to go with CEX.IO.  However, if I had to choose a company to cloud mine with I would choose cloudhashing.com.  To me, they&amp;#39;re kind of like the underdogs.  They&amp;#39;re the smaller guys and they offer a better price per gigahash.  Now there is one thing that I do want to point out and that&amp;#39;s their terms and conditions.  Now under their mining product in their terms and conditions they break down the percentages that they take from your profits.  We collect 10% of the Bitcoin you make for management fees for operation of the pool.  They also collect 30% of the Bitcoin we make which is reinvested into their mining rig.  So, this is something to consider.  But even still that they take this much out of our profit I would still go with them because their cost per gigahash is so much lower than CEX.IO.
&lt;p&gt;
So remember, cost per gigahash is the key to cloud mining and making your money back and then making a profit.  Don&amp;#39;t forget to factor in all the maintenance fees and any hidden costs that might be associated with each company.  Now, for those of you who want to participate in my free Bitcoin giveaway contest Round 2 here&amp;#39;s how to play.  Step one, comment on this video in the comment section below.  Step two, like the comments you see from other YouTube users.  You can like as many YouTube comments that you want to.  The top five most liked comments from different YouTube users will receive $15 in Bitcoin.  I will send you the coin in two weeks to any address that you specify when the contest is over.  The contest will end on December, 31st 2013.  So like I said earlier I think this will be a lot of fun and it will put the contest in the hands of the YouTube users because you all will be deciding who should win the contest.  If only a few people like other people&amp;#39;s comments it&amp;#39;s going to be extremely easy for the top five comments to win.
&lt;p&gt;
In Part 5, I&amp;#39;m going to go over online shopping with Bitcoin and what types of goods we can buy and where we can shop online using our Bitcoin.  So, make sure to subscribe and I&amp;#39;ll be seeing you in Part 5.  Good luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - TOP 6 Gift Card Websites Using BitCoin - Website Reviews - Online Shopping - Part 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to Bitcoin for Beginners Part 5.  In Part 4, we went over cloud mining or cloud hashing.  In Part 5, we&amp;#39;ll take a look at where you can spend your Bitcoin online.  I&amp;#39;m going to be going through some gift card reviews for some websites where you can purchase gift cards using your Bitcoin.  But before we get started, I wanted to congratulate last week&amp;#39;s winners in Round 2 of the Free Bitcoin Giveaway Contest.  Now the winners had the most likes on their YouTube comments and that was a lot of fun.  Some of those comments were hilarious.  Thank you to everyone who participated.
&lt;p&gt;
Now we&amp;#39;re going to have another contest in this video, but I&amp;#39;ll get into that a little bit later.  And first, let&amp;#39;s continue with Part 5 of the Bitcoin for Beginners video series.  People are buying all sorts of things with Bitcoin from houses to electric cars, to small islands.  People are even buying their way into space using Bitcoin.  But for most of you, you&amp;#39;re not looking to buy a house, you&amp;#39;re looking for every day goods and services like food and retail items.  So where can you spend your Bitcoin and actually buy these things that you want or need.  You need resources, you need real things and this is what I want to show you.
&lt;p&gt;
I am going to start with a few cool things that I found and then get into the Walmart, the Best Buy, the Amazon.com, the Target gift card options for the US customers as well as people who reside in Europe and Australia.
&lt;p&gt;
Now the first place I want to show you is really just for kicks.  It&amp;#39;s called pizzaforcoins.com.  And pizzaforcoins.com will work for the United States, the United Kingdom which is temporarily disabled, Australia and soon Canada.  So you just select where you live and they will allow you to purchase pizza from Domino&amp;#39;s, Pizza Hut or Papa John&amp;#39;s.  And so basically what you do is, you choose the establishment where you want to order your pizza from, you pay them for the order you place your order on their website and then they will place the order with Domino&amp;#39;s and then Domino&amp;#39;s will deliver it to your house.  So, the point is it&amp;#39;s just a way for you to purchase Domino&amp;#39;s Pizza or Pizza Hut or Papa John&amp;#39;s pizza using Bitcoin.  There&amp;#39;d be no other way for you to do that really.  You’d have to either exchange your Bitcoin into cash and order it that way but these guys allow you to do it directly through their website.  So I just wanted to point that out.  Kind of cool!
&lt;p&gt;
The next place I want to show you is BitcoinShop.US.  So, once again, only for US residents only but this is a huge website.  They have a lot of categories that you can purchase items with Bitcoin.  Now I just want to point one thing out with websites like BitcoinShop.US and BitcoinShop.US and that is all of these products have a markup.  So, all of these products are going to cost a little bit more money because you&amp;#39;re using Bitcoin than if you&amp;#39;re using dollars or euros.  So, just to give you an idea let&amp;#39;s just take this chromecast here.  If I were to buy this chromecast off of BitcoinShop.US, you could see that it&amp;#39;s going to cost me .047 Bitcoins.  If I head over to Coinbase and I punch in .04 I&amp;#39;ll get the exchange rate.  That&amp;#39;s $38, $39 after my fees.  Now I use Coinbase as my exchange, as my bank.  I recommend them but that&amp;#39;s just another story.  They are simple and easy to use.  But you could see here that .047 is worth $39.  But if I were to just search Google for the chromecast you can see that I can buy it off of eBay for $21.  So $21 versus 39 that&amp;#39;s about an 80% markup to purchase the chromecast off of BitcoinShop.US.  Now, I&amp;#39;m not saying that all of their products are going to have an 80% markup.  This is just a great example of how some of their products, if not most of them, there is a markup.  So, just something to look out for.  I just want to point out before you start purchasing things with Bitcoin and not realizing how much they&amp;#39;re worth.  Basically just do the conversion before you make a purchase.
&lt;p&gt;
Coinmap.org.  Coinmap.org is just really cool because we can search the world of places that accept Bitcoin and Litecoin.  In the top right hand corner we can select these two currencies and we can select any of these countries.  We can zoom in on this map and we can see all of the places that accept Bitcoin.  Now these aren&amp;#39;t all of the places but these are the places that are registered on coinmap.org.  So, I could take Spain for example and we could just zoom in to Madrid and basically see the establishments that accept Bitcoin in Spain.  And you can do this with your country.  So, I encourage you to go to coinmap.com, check out your backyard and see if any places are accepting Bitcoin or Litecoin where you live.  So, this is really cool.  I wanted to just point it out because it pertains to everybody.
&lt;p&gt;
Now let&amp;#39;s get into the best part of this video.  I am going to review the six best places to purchase gift cards using Bitcoin.  Now the reason why you want to purchase gift cards or you would purchase gift cards is because right now you can purchase gift cards using Bitcoin and then use those gift cards to purchase other goods from places like Walmart, Target, even places like McDonald&amp;#39;s, Burger King just to name some of the most popular establishments that you can buy gift cards for.  Now there&amp;#39;s a huge variety and there are quite a few websites that allow you to do this but I&amp;#39;ve compiled a list of the top six and I am going to go through them right now.
&lt;p&gt;
The first website that I want to show you and this is ranked number 6 and this is giftcardbtc.com.  Now giftcardbtc.com is -- I have ranked number 6 because it doesn&amp;#39;t have much of a selection.  We can only order Amazon gift cards and that&amp;#39;s it.  Not a huge following if I click on their Twitter.  You know they only have a thousand followers.  So they&amp;#39;re not that large of a company and I would feel better going with a company that has a larger following.  It&amp;#39;s just -- I think credibility goes hand in hand with that.  I can read other people&amp;#39;s comments and experience with the company.  So, this company giftcardbtc.com looks great.  You know I think it&amp;#39;s great that they&amp;#39;re offering this as a service but I believe that they come in sixth place out of the websites that I reviewed.
&lt;p&gt;
The next website I want to show you, number 5 is, itradebtc.com.  Now itradebtc.com is number 5 because there are downloadable gift cards and you can basically pay in Bitcoin and then download the gift card in pdf form.  Now this is great and this is one of the best things going for itradebtc.com.  However, the reason why they are fifth is because the gift cards that people want the most which I believe are the gift card credit cards like these Visa prepaid credit cards, they&amp;#39;re out of stock.  And they&amp;#39;ve been out of stock for quite some time.  I hope they re-up their stock on these gift cards but it&amp;#39;s just the simple fact that the best cards that they offer they&amp;#39;re out of stock.
&lt;p&gt;
The next website that I want to show you is number 4 and that&amp;#39;s bitcc.herokuapp.com.  Not sure how that&amp;#39;s supposed to be pronounced but here&amp;#39;s the address.  And this pertains to people in Europe.  Now you can buy a Visa prepaid debit card all the way up to €100 and you can see here that they have little bit of information about these cards.  Some of these cards will not be anonymous.  Some of these are 90% percent anonymous.  This one&amp;#39;s a 100% anonymous.  So, for the people who live in Europe this can be a fantastic option for you if you&amp;#39;re looking to dump Bitcoin into gift cards or prepaid debit cards.  If you head over to their Frequently Asked Questions page you can see that you can add this money to your PayPal account.  So, that&amp;#39;s huge for a lot of people I know.
&lt;p&gt;
Number 3 is going to be egifter.com.  Now egifter.com is great.  They’re a little bit larger.  They offer what I&amp;#39;ve noticed is a lot more food options for gift cards you can see T.G.I. Friday&amp;#39;s here.  I know they also have Chili&amp;#39;s.  So, egifter.com is just a great website.  They have a huge selection of gift cards and you can basically just browse their gift cards and, like I said, they have a lot of gift cards pertaining to food.  Here&amp;#39;s an Applebee&amp;#39;s card.  I believe this is going to be only for the United States but you can see that they don&amp;#39;t have the Walmart gift card which is huge.  So, that&amp;#39;s one of the reasons why I&amp;#39;ve ranked them as number 3.
&lt;p&gt;
Moving forward, number 2 is going to be giftcardzen.com.  Giftcardzen.com is number 2 because you can be in the United States or in Europe and when you go to Giftcardzen it should recognize where you&amp;#39;re from and it will tell you that you can either buy electronic gift cards or physical gift cards or both or one of the other.  So, giftcardzen.com is great.  And the reason why giftcardzen.com is number 2 is because they have a huge selection of Target and Walmart gift cards.  Another reason why they&amp;#39;re number 2 is because when you buy the gift card here&amp;#39;s a $900 Target gift card.  It&amp;#39;s an electronic gift card which means they&amp;#39;ll email you the pdf gift card which is instant.  But you&amp;#39;re only paying 848.  So, in this case you&amp;#39;re saving a little bit of money.  So, Giftcardzen allows you to purchase these gift cards at a discount.  So I think that&amp;#39;s great.  They allow gift cards up to over a $1000.  So, if you&amp;#39;re trying to really get rid of some Bitcoin and exchange it into cash this is a great way to do it using gift cards at your favorite retailer.  So, Target and Walmart they carry just about everything that&amp;#39;s why I&amp;#39;m showing you these two retailers.  But if we go back to Giftcardzen we can search all of them and we can see that they basically have a huge offering of gift card options.
&lt;p&gt;
Moving forward the number 1 gift card website that I found is only available for the US.  But it&amp;#39;s number 1 because it is definitely the most widely used, widely trusted and you can find the most information about it and that&amp;#39;s gift.com.  Huge shout out to gift.com.  You can see here on their main page these are some of the most popular gift cards JCPenney, Regal for movies, Burger King, CVS, which I like.  But we can just browse their gift cards and we can see all of the places that they offer.  They don&amp;#39;t offer any Walmart gift cards.  You would have to go to Giftcardzen to do that.  But they do offer Target, which is almost just as good.  So if you&amp;#39;re trying to find the safest way, most legit way, the most proven way to purchase gift cards using Bitcoin it&amp;#39;s going to be through gift.com.  If you live outside of the United States go ahead and try giftcardzen.com.  Both of these guys are really good in my opinion.  So Gift&amp;#39;s going to take the number 1 spot.  They also offer amazon.com gift cards, another popular gift card.  And they offer amazon.com gift cards up to $2000.  So, huge, huge limits and gift.com has a massive social media following.  We can just click on the Facebook gift.com, 15,000 likes and we can read other people&amp;#39;s comments and experiences with Gift.
&lt;p&gt;
So, that wraps up the gift card review with gift.com taking the number 1 spot.  Giftcardzen coming in second and egifter rounding out the top three.
&lt;p&gt;
Now let&amp;#39;s get into the contest for this video.  This is going to be Round 3 of the Free Bitcoin Giveaway Contest.  Here&amp;#39;s how to play.  Step one, like this video and share it on your social media platforms.  Step two, comment on this video.  The top four YouTube comments that have the most likes will receive $15 in Bitcoin.  I will send you the Bitcoin in two weeks to any address you specify when this contest ends.  The contest will end February 7th, 2014.  Once again, this should be a lot of fun.  And while you&amp;#39;re at it let me know of a video you&amp;#39;d like to see me create and I&amp;#39;ll give you and your company a shout-out or promote your cause.
&lt;p&gt;
Thank you for watching.  I really hope you enjoy this one and I&amp;#39;ll be sure to see you in the next video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/bitcoin-mining-for-beginners-how-to-mine-bitcoins/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/bitcoin-mining-for-beginners-how-to-mine-bitcoins/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Litecoin mining? Learn all you need to get started.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weusecoins.com/what-is-litecoin/&quot;&gt;What is Litecoin?&lt;/a&gt; Want to learn how to mine litecoins? First, mining litecoins is done via scrypt instead of SHA256.
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tf3s-zBTNoQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started mining litecoins you could get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/70khslitecoinminer&quot;&gt;70KHs litecoin miner&lt;/a&gt; for about $100 or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/30mhslitecoinminer&quot;&gt;30MHs litecoin miner&lt;/a&gt; for about $285.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cKjiw7nAZYc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to buy Litecoin with USD; with EUR; with RUR; and with BTC or practically every currency in the world.
&lt;p&gt;Finding the easiest way to buy LiteCoin, minding the nature of cryptocurrencies and methods of converting them. If you exchange your currency into cryptocurrency then it becomes extremely easy to then diversify and trade other forms of cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Want to learn how to mine Litecoins on Mac?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NRSZT2emHw4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To get started mining litecoins you could get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/70khsdogecoinminer&quot;&gt;70KHs litecoin miner&lt;/a&gt; for about $100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Want to learn how to mine Litecoins on Windows?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gASgyuXUoF8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - What is Litecoin mining?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to the Litecoin For Beginners video series.  Litecoin is a virtual currency that has emerged as the second most popular and widely accepted cryptocurrency in the world.  Bitcoin is currently ranked number one and if you want to watch a Bitcoin For Beginners video, you can click here.  But in this video, I&amp;#39;m going to quickly cover what Litecoin is, how it differs from bitcoin in the easiest way to use our computers to mine Litecoin for us.
&lt;p&gt;So Litecoin is a cryptocurrency and cryptocurrencies allow you to send and receive information from one person to another instantly with incredible encryption properties.  Now this strength and security for transactions is what really attracts so many people to use it, especially to exchange money and value.
&lt;p&gt;There are a few differences between bitcoin and Litecoin.  For one, the number of total coins that can be created within the open source protocol. So with bitcoin, twenty-one million bitcoins can be created.  But with Litecoin, eighty-four million Litecoins can be created.  Secondly, the amount of time that it takes the network to create new coins is a little different.  The bitcoin network creates twenty-five coins every ten minutes.  The Litecoin network creates fifty coins every two and a half minutes.  Now I&amp;#39;m not going to say why that&amp;#39;s good or bad.  A lot of people have different takes on that.  However, like bitcoin, each Litecoin can&amp;#39;t be subdivided into a hundred million smaller units.  And that&amp;#39;s defined by eight decimal places.  So each one point of Litecoin can be divided into a hundred million smaller units.
&lt;p&gt;Now that we understand a little bit more about Litecoin, let&amp;#39;s begin with the Litecoin For Beginners video series.  Now in part one, we&amp;#39;re going to accomplish a few things.  The first thing we&amp;#39;re going to do is set up our Litecoin wallets so that we can send and receive Litecoins.
&lt;p&gt;Now the second thing we&amp;#39;re going to do is, we&amp;#39;re going to download and configure our mining software so that we can use our graphics processor to mine Litecoin for us.  Now as a reminder, I just want to point out that everything that I&amp;#39;m going to be talking about in this video, I&amp;#39;m going to have a download link in the video description.  So if you want to skip the tutorial and download all of the software, go ahead and try it out.
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;#39;s get started.  First things first, let&amp;#39;s go download the Litecoin wallet.  And we want to make sure that we go to Litecoin.org to download the Litecoin wallet.  This is a trusted source and we can download the Litecoin wallet for Windows, Mac or Linux.  I have already downloaded the wallet and you can see here&amp;#39;s my shortcut.  I&amp;#39;ve already installed it.  Now I can launch the Litecoin wallet and you&amp;#39;ll see that when it starts, we&amp;#39;ll see a little splash screen here.
&lt;p&gt;And then when it loads, it&amp;#39;s going to attempt to connect to the Litecoin network, and it&amp;#39;s going to try and sync.  But just let it do its things, see now it&amp;#39;s down to ten from eleven.  So it goes fairly quickly.  The first thing that we want to do is click on receive.  And we&amp;#39;re going to create a new address.  So click on new address.  And let&amp;#39;s give this address a name.  Okay.  Click on okay.  You&amp;#39;ll see your address pop up here.
&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;#39;s nothing that we&amp;#39;re going to do with this address right now, but we need it later in the video.  So let&amp;#39;s minimize our wallet.  The next thing we&amp;#39;ll want to do is download the mining software.  And so for this example, we&amp;#39;ll be using my favorite software called GUIMiner scrypt.  Now this is the easiest software to use.  Anyone can use it.  And I&amp;#39;m going to show you exactly what to put in.  So we can download GUIMiner-scrypt from guiminer.org.  This is the original website to download the program.
&lt;p&gt;You could see here that there&amp;#39;s a download link for Windows.  And if I click on that, I&amp;#39;ll get a little thing here that says &amp;quot;This file is malicious, and chrome has blocked it.&amp;quot;  You can dismiss that.  It&amp;#39;s not malicious.  You might need to go into your settings and configure them to allow you to download this program.  If you&amp;#39;re having trouble downloading it, go ahead and click on this link here.  Have a look at the official forum thread on Bitcointalk.
&lt;p&gt;If we click on that link there, that will bring us to the official thread and we can download the program from here.  So that will work as well to download GUIMiner-scrypt.  Go ahead and download that program.  I&amp;#39;ve already done that.  And so here is the folder that I&amp;#39;ve downloaded.  Here is GUIMiner-scrypt.  I&amp;#39;ll just double-click on the EXE file, minimize that.  And it should pop up after launching the program.
&lt;p&gt;Here is the program, but I have no idea what to put in any of these text boxes.  So let&amp;#39;s go through this one at a time and I&amp;#39;ll tell you what to put in.  So the first thing that we need to do is we need to find a host.  So we&amp;#39;re going to join a pool.  Now the pool that we&amp;#39;re going to join in this example is going to be wemineltc.com.  But if we check out this website here, Litecoinpool.org/pools, we can see a nice pie chart of all the major pools and their market share in the Litecoin network.
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#39;m going to be showing you WeMineLTC.  And this is the largest pool, but they weren&amp;#39;t the largest pool when I created my account.  And by no means, is a pool any better because it&amp;#39;s larger.  So I definitely encourage you to try out these other pools, like, Coinotron, Give Me Coins, LiteGuardian, because these pools might be better than WeMineLTC.  However, I&amp;#39;ve already created my account with WeMineLTC.  So that&amp;#39;s the account that I&amp;#39;ll be showing you.
&lt;p&gt;Also, I want to point out this other resource that I found: it&amp;#39;s the Litecoin.info/Mining&lt;em&gt;pool&lt;/em&gt;comparison.  And we can compare all of the pools.  In this chart, we can see there&amp;#39;s wemineltc.com.  And this would just kind of give us a little bit more information, especially on the fees for that pool and we can just kind of do our homework on the pool.  So I definitely recommend checking out the pool that you plan out joining before you join it.
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll just go to wemineltc.com, and I&amp;#39;ve already created an account.  So you&amp;#39;ll need to create an account, click on my account.  The first thing that we&amp;#39;re going to do is change your automatic payout threshold here.  Right now it&amp;#39;s on zero, but I&amp;#39;m going to change it from zero to one.  And this means that every time, my computer mines one Litecoin, it&amp;#39;s going to automatically send it to my wallet.
&lt;p&gt;So put in my four-digit pin that I created when I created my account.  And I&amp;#39;ll click on update settings, and that will update that automatic payout threshold setting.  The second thing I&amp;#39;m going to do is change my payment address.  So I&amp;#39;m going to go back into my wallet, hit the receive tab.  Remember that address that we created, you want to right click on it, copy address, and we&amp;#39;re going to paste that address into this text box.
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re going to enter our four-digit pin again.  And we&amp;#39;re then going to click on send email code.  That&amp;#39;s going to send a code to our email account.  Once we get that code, we&amp;#39;ll put in our four-digit pin again and we&amp;#39;ll put in the code that they emailed to us and then we&amp;#39;ll click on change address.  And that will change our payment address.  And so that means every time we mine one Litecoin, it will automatically send that Litecoin to this address, which is the address in my wallet.
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;#39;ve configured our WeMineLTC account, we need to create a worker.  And we&amp;#39;ll click on my account, my workers.  Now we need to create a worker, and so we can add a new worker down here at the bottom and we can really put in anything we want here.  This is just a name for our worker.  So let&amp;#39;s just do beginners, my password, make it simple, one, two, three.  It&amp;#39;s really not important.  And then we&amp;#39;ll click on add new worker.
&lt;p&gt;And when we do that, we&amp;#39;ll see that the worker now has been created.  Here it is.  And so we&amp;#39;re going to need this information in just a second.  Right on the main page, we can see the servers here.  So we&amp;#39;re going to choose, just the first server for this example.  But you can see there are a number of servers in the United States, in Asia.  And this is really so that if you&amp;#39;re trying one of these servers and you can&amp;#39;t connect, you can try a different server and see if that server is just experiencing problems.
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;#39;s bring up our GUIMiner.  And the very first thing that we need is they host.  And if we hover over this text box, we see a little hint there.  It says host addresses or host address without the http prefix.  So we&amp;#39;ll need everything after the slashes here.  So I&amp;#39;ll just copy and paste this first host, everything to the dotcom, just like that.  And then I&amp;#39;ll copy that, go back to the miner, we&amp;#39;ll paste that in there.  Okay.  It should look very similar.
&lt;p&gt;But the port is three, three, three, four.  So make sure that the port here three, three, three, four.  Now the user name is going to be our worker that we just created.  So here&amp;#39;s my worker, I&amp;#39;ll copy and paste the worker name right there.  My password was very simple, just one, two, three.
&lt;p&gt;Now my device is going to be my graphics card, which is this one here.  You can see my processor, my CPU is available. And I could select that.  But my graphics processor, which is this one here, it&amp;#39;s going to be about a hundred times faster than my processor.  So, you know, choose whatever you can and see what works, see what doesn&amp;#39;t work.  If you don&amp;#39;t see your processor or your graphics processor listed here, you may need to update your drivers.  Here are the two links for AMD drivers.  I&amp;#39;ll provide these two links in the video description.
&lt;p&gt;Just go to these links and download the latest drivers for your graphics card and install them.  But first, let&amp;#39;s just try mining with your setup right now.  And then the next thing that we&amp;#39;ll need to set is our threat concurrency.  So let&amp;#39;s just put ninety-two hundred here.  In all of the settings that I&amp;#39;m going to be entering here are really good, just baseline starting point numbers.
&lt;p&gt;And so ninety-two hundred, let&amp;#39;s put vectors, the default value was one.  GPU Thread, the default value was one.  Work size, default is two fifty-six.  Now the intensity, this is really where -- this is -- this number here is going to make the biggest difference in your kilohertz per second or your megahertz per second speeds.  So intensity, twenty is really high; ten is really low.  So I&amp;#39;m going to choose something right in the middle.  I think fifteen is good.
&lt;p&gt;We want to make sure stratum is clicked yes.  And we&amp;#39;re going to click on start.  Now it&amp;#39;s either going to work or it&amp;#39;s not going to work.  You can see that it&amp;#39;s working for me.  And my speed is a hundred and seventy-nine kilohertz per second.  If it doesn&amp;#39;t work for you, the very first thing that you should try is selecting something in this drop-down.  Because I noticed that if I didn&amp;#39;t select something in this drop-down, sometimes I had glitches.  So let&amp;#39;s just select sixty-nine, seventy, okay?  It&amp;#39;s going to change some of these numbers.
&lt;p&gt;Really, it&amp;#39;s only going to change this number and this number, which are fine.  And let&amp;#39;s just keep all of these numbers like we haven&amp;#39;t and click on start.  And you might find that by selecting something in the GPU default, it helps you out and it works for some reason.  So you can see that now I&amp;#39;m actually mining faster than I was before.  I was at a hundred and seventy-nine kilohertz per second before, now I&amp;#39;m at a hundred and eighty-eight kilohertz&amp;#39;s, two hundred kilohertz&amp;#39;s per second.
&lt;p&gt;And the only number that really changed was this number here and my intensity.  So if we increase our threat concurrency, and this is in kilobytes, we can increase our speed.  So I&amp;#39;m going to bump the intensity up two-twenty.  And I&amp;#39;m going to bump this up to nine thousand.  And I&amp;#39;m going to click on start.  And I bet it&amp;#39;s higher than two hundred kilohertz&amp;#39;s per second.  But you will want to be careful, because if you go too high, you know, if you bump this intensity up to a hundred, it probably won&amp;#39;t make a difference over twenty or twenty-five.
&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;#39;s going to really slow down your computer and it&amp;#39;s -- it might be bad for your graphics processors.  It could potentially burn them out, overheat them.  All in all, these are good numbers to go with, to start off and to see what your speed is for mining.  And then you can increase the intensity or increase the thread concurrency a little bit as you see fit, to see if you get better results.  Now if you let this run, let&amp;#39;s just say, overnight.  And you mine Litecoin all night, all of your statistics are going to be kept in your WeMineLTC profile.
&lt;p&gt;So if I click on stats, I can get to my stats here and my dashboard here on the left-hand side.  So that&amp;#39;s it.  That&amp;#39;s the easiest way to mine Litecoin.  I hope you enjoy part one of the Litecoin For Beginners video series.  Please rate, comment and subscribe.  In part two, I&amp;#39;ll be going over where do we exchange our money into Litecoin.  In case, we&amp;#39;re having problems mining or maybe our computer isn&amp;#39;t fast enough to mine, whatever the reason maybe.
&lt;p&gt;So thank you so much for watching.  And I&amp;#39;ll see you in part two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - LiteCoin For Beginners - How To Buy LiteCoin &amp;amp; Exchange Reviews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add transcript here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - Litecoin Mining on Mac&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All right.  I&amp;#39;m going to walk you through how to start mining Litecoin on your Mac computer.  The first thing you need to do is join a Litecoin pool using CoinHunter.  It&amp;#39;s a popular one right now.  It doesn&amp;#39;t really matter.  You can find tons online.  When you get to one of these sites, first thing you need to do is create an account for the site.  You can click that button down there.  There&amp;#39;s a lot of fields you have to sign out, or you have to fill out to sign up.  I&amp;#39;m not going to do it for you because I already have an account, I&amp;#39;m just going to go back to the home page and login directly.
&lt;p&gt;All right.  So once you are in, this is what the interior of the mining pool website looks like.  All you really need to do in here is go to your account to Workers, which is on the sidebar there.  Click that.  And then you just need to create a new worker.
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to go ahead and create one.  I&amp;#39;ll call it worker 2, I&amp;#39;ll make the password worker 2, as well.  Just create that worker.  You can see now that there is a new worker created.  At this point, there&amp;#39;s a few things you&amp;#39;re going to need to remember that we&amp;#39;ll use later.  The first is your username, which is Ardo in my case.  The next is the worker name, which in this case is worker 2.  And then you also have to know the worker password, which in this case is worker 2, as well.  The last thing you need to know is the host name of this pool, which you can find in help.  Getting started, you&amp;#39;ll see some for different continents.  I&amp;#39;m in North America.  So I&amp;#39;m going to go ahead and highlight and copy one of the ones in North America and we&amp;#39;ll use that.  We&amp;#39;ll use that later.
&lt;p&gt;All right.  So the next thing you need to do is download the actual software to do the mining.  That&amp;#39;s available at SourceForge.  That&amp;#39;s called CPU Miner.  Go ahead and download that.  The link&amp;#39;s in the description.  It will started your download and while this is going, let&amp;#39;s go over to finder, check out our Downloads folder.  You&amp;#39;ll see that it&amp;#39;s a zip file, so you&amp;#39;re going to need to expand that.
&lt;p&gt;So go ahead and double-click that, it will expand, you&amp;#39;ll see this minerd executable, which is basically the program that we&amp;#39;re going to run to mine.  Now to run this, we need to use an application called Terminal.  You can find that in your applications folder under Utilities.  It should be all the way at the bottom here, yep, double click it.  You open up a Terminal, it looks like this.
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re not comfortable with it, that&amp;#39;s fine, I&amp;#39;m going tell you exactly what&amp;#39;s you need to type to get this running, then you start with CD downloads, which is going to take you into the Downloads folder, basically, which is right at minerd file list.  You then need to change the permissions on minerd.  So, you type chmod 755 minerd, which is going to allow you to run the file.
&lt;p&gt;And then you&amp;#39;re ready to run it, you need to dot, slash, minerd.  The first thing you need is dash O and then you paste that host name that you copied earlier.  The next thing you need is dash U, which is going to be your username.  You need to put your pool username dot your worker name.  So in my case, it&amp;#39;s ardo.worker2.  After that, you need dash P, which is going to be your worker password.  In my case, this is worker 2, as well.
&lt;p&gt;Then just go ahead and hit enter and you&amp;#39;ll see that the program is now running and you are -- you&amp;#39;re mining for Litecoins.  So I&amp;#39;m going to jump ahead now.  This has been running for about thirty minutes.  You can see it&amp;#39;s still going.  The hash rate is a little higher now.  But more importantly, you see these accepted messages which means that you are, in fact, generating valid Litecoins.
&lt;p&gt;If you zoom out now and go back to that mining pool website, go ahead and refresh that.  You can confirm that this is working here, as well.  You&amp;#39;ll see that you now have a hash rate, which means your program is running at that given rate.  You can confirm down here, as well.  You can take a look at your specific worker and see that that worker definitely is generating hashes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - Litecoin Mining on Windows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey there!  So in this video I&amp;#39;m going to show you how you can mine Litecoins on Windows.  And there&amp;#39;s basically two ways that people tend to do it and first one is by using CPU miner which uses your computer&amp;#39;s processor to do the mining and then there is GPU mining which uses your graphics card for the mining.  And the GPU mining tends to be faster, but CPU mining is still useable.  So but you can basically run both of them at the same time to maximize your yield.  And most people do this through a mining pool, just because it&amp;#39;s more efficient that way.  Otherwise it will just take ages for you to do anything unless you have like a huge computer farm or you can have like massive amounts of hashing power available, but usually for hobbies and the general normal people doing it through a mining pool usually ends ups being the better choice.
&lt;p&gt;So to get started you&amp;#39;re going to have to download the Litecoin wallet application and you can do that from Litecoin.org.  And there is versions available for Windows, Linux and Mac, but I&amp;#39;m just going to go through the Windows version this time.  So once you&amp;#39;ve done that and you&amp;#39;ve installed the Litecoin wallets then what you want to do is you want to create maybe create a new address.  You can use the main one here.  Oh, yeah.  And here you&amp;#39;ll have the synchronizing bar here.  It will take like hours to synchronize this stuff.  What you want to do is you want to maybe create a new one for your mining pool.  Like I&amp;#39;m using Burnside&amp;#39;s Litecoin mining pools.  And I made this address for it, for this computer.  As you can see I just installed this like a few hours ago.  It&amp;#39;s still at like 30 weeks behind.  But, yeah, basically once you&amp;#39;ve done that like click in here a new address, entered a label and once you&amp;#39;ve done that click okay and it will automatically generate an address there.  And then you click on that, on the label and click on copy address and you&amp;#39;ll have the address on your clipboard.
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#39;ve done that you should go and create an account on Burnside&amp;#39;s mining pool site which is ltc.kattare.com.  And once you&amp;#39;re here you click on register and you enter your details in here and then you just click the register button.  And you don&amp;#39;t need to verify your email or anything so you can just log in straight away.  And once you&amp;#39;re logged in you can go ahead to your account settings and here under account settings here you can enter your payment address which is the one you&amp;#39;ve just created in your wallets and copy it to your clipboard.  So you just paste that stuff in here and enter your pin code.  Yeah, you have to remember your pin code and then click update account settings.
&lt;p&gt;So what that will do is it will enable you to start mining, because now they have an address where they pay your yield.  And next thing to do would be to create new workers, if you&amp;#39;re going to use both CPU and GPU mining.  What I did here like that they have by default there is one worker and had a default password is X.  But what I did here is I just for esthetics more or less I created these two, one for the CPU miner and one for the GPU miner.  And yeah, basically how you do that is down here you just type like GPU 2 and add password, whatever.  And then click add worker.  You have it there, but I&amp;#39;m not going to use that so just click delete.
&lt;p&gt;And yeah, once you&amp;#39;re done here you can move on and download the mining software.  And one of them is CPU miner which you can find in here on this thread at bitcointalk.org.  And I&amp;#39;ll have all these links and stuff in my description and on my website so don&amp;#39;t worry about that.  You can check it out from there.  Basically, yeah, here is the CPU miners available in 32 bit, 64 bit versions for Windows and I&amp;#39;m using the 64 bit one.  So you just download it from here and then you extract it to your desired location.  I put it actually in my Litecoin folder.  I made another folder called miners.  And then I put both the CPU and a GPU miner in here.  So that&amp;#39;s what I did, but you can do it differently of course.
&lt;p&gt;But any way extract it to your desired location and then you need to make a BAT file so that you can like log into the Kattare -- to Burnside&amp;#39;s Litecoin mining pool.  And the way I did that as like on my desktop here for example.  It&amp;#39;s just an example.  You can right click and make in your text document.  Now if you have the suffixes here so that you can see them, you can edit that and just rename it BAT.  And then rename the file to minerd&lt;em&gt;64.  Just click yes and then you right click that and edit.  And what you want to put here is minerd.exe - o &lt;a href=&quot;http://ltc.kattare.com-9332/&quot;&gt;http://ltc.kattare.com-9332&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;#39;s the port number and then space - O and this is for your user name and password and space and user name.  This is where you put your -- you don&amp;#39;t type username.  Type your name that you created for the website and then dot workers suffix.  And that&amp;#39;s the one like CPU1 that I put in here.  This one.  That&amp;#39;s the suffix, worker suffix.  And colon worker password and that&amp;#39;s the worker password here, that one.
&lt;p&gt;And then you just go ahead.  Well, you can still -- I&amp;#39;ll put the Q there it just make quite, but there&amp;#39;s a bunch of options here if you go with your like CMD EXE file or whatever like in your command prompt.  And you go here and you type minerd help.  Then you&amp;#39;ll see all these different options here like threads.  By default it has number -- the number of threads attached by default is the number of processors you have but you can modify that as well by, you know, putting T like if I want like one thread then I just dash T space one and so on.  And then you basically just save that and then from your desktop, control C, copy it and then you paste it in here where your mining executable file is.  But this needs to be in the same folder.  And then after that you can create like a shortcut of the BAT file to your desktop.  Like that.  And then you just run it off that when you want to mine.
&lt;p&gt;And yeah, so the next one would be the GPU miner.  The Cudaminer is only for NVidia graphics cards.  There&amp;#39;s a different one for Radeon graphics cards which you find here on the Burnside&amp;#39;s site.  You go here to get started.  Click on get started.  Once you&amp;#39;re logged in and then it will show you these details here.  And basically CG Miner and a Reaper GPU miner they&amp;#39;re both for Radeon series graphics cards.  But I don&amp;#39;t have any of those graphics cards so I can&amp;#39;t really use them.  But you can download Cudaminer.  I&amp;#39;m just going to show you how to set up Cudaminer.
&lt;p&gt;You can download it from this thread at Bitcointalk called Cudaminer, a new Litecoin mining application Windows/Linux.  And you download the newest version which has a 32 bit and 64 bit version in the same zip file as well as the source code in case you want to compile it on Linux or compile it on Windows yourself to make some tweaks or whatever.
&lt;p&gt;And you basically extract.  What I did I extracted the whole thing into my download folder and then I went into the, I guess, the 64 bit folder and copied that here and the I renamed it to this and what it will have is a BAT file a bit like this but it&amp;#39;s slightly different because Cudaminer uses stratum.  So it will have a different address when you want to connect to that.  So you do the same process, like make a new file, cudaminer&lt;/em&gt;64.bit and then you enter this stuff in here and the main difference being at the address stratum + ttp://ltc-stratum.kattare.com and the port is different as well, 3333.
&lt;p&gt;But otherwise it&amp;#39;s basically the same because Cudaminer is based off of the CPU miner so it has a lot of the same, you know, configurations and stuff.  But, yeah, once you&amp;#39;re done there you just go ahead and copy paste it in here to your Cudaminer directory.  And then you make another shortcut for the BAT file.  And then you run it off of that and, yeah, as you can see it&amp;#39;s working and mine with this right now.  Control C to terminate and this is working as well.
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#39;s how you mine Litecoin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-litecoin-mining/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-litecoin-mining/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Dogecoin mining? Learn all you need to get started.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weusecoins.com/what-is-dogecoin/&quot;&gt;What is Dogecoin?&lt;/a&gt; Want to learn how to mine dogecoins? First, mining dogecoins is done via scrypt instead of SHA256.
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yNpfilTliqE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started mining dogecoins you could get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/70khsdogecoinminer&quot;&gt;70KHs Dogecoin miner&lt;/a&gt; for about $100 or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/30mhslitecoinminer&quot;&gt;30MHs Dogecoin miner&lt;/a&gt; for about $285.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to learn how to mine dogecoins on Mac?
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i8zEvOqR-ms&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started mining dogecoins you could get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/70khsdogecoinminer&quot;&gt;70KHs litecoin miner&lt;/a&gt; for about $100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to learn how to mine dogecoins on Windows?
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zOqZ_sHfJ_U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - What is Dogecoin mining?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to my Dogecoin mining tutorial. Today I&amp;#39;m going to teach you how to mine Dogecoins quickly and easily with your Windows PC with an AMD video card. So first thing&amp;#39;s first. You&amp;#39;re going to need a wallet. And the Dogecoin wallet is just a piece of software that keeps your Dogecoins on your computer, unless you send and receive them.
&lt;p&gt;So you want to go to Dodgecoin.com. I have a link in my video description. And just click on Windows and it will download the latest version. I already have it downloaded and on my desktop just for this video. So once you&amp;#39;ve done that you want to extract into a folder. Just drag that into a folder. And inside you&amp;#39;ll see Dogecoinqt.exc. And open that. And it might take a minute or so.
&lt;p&gt;Okay. So now that your wallet&amp;#39;s open it will say out of sync next to wallet. And that just means that it has not synchronized with the Dogecoin network yet. Mine has already been synchronized and I&amp;#39;m just going to blackout some of these parts just for privacy reasons, but on the bottom right here you&amp;#39;ll see a progress bar and just regular progress bar. And after an hour or so the progress bar should complete. And that should mean that it is in sync with the Dogecoin network. Once that is synchronized, your client will be able to receive and send Dogecoins. Okay. So you can open this and leave it to sync while you&amp;#39;re mining. So you can just minimize that for now.
&lt;p&gt;So to start mining we&amp;#39;re going to use a software CG Miner. And again I have the link in the download -- in the video description. So once you go to that link, you want to go to CG Miner 3.7.2 Windows ZIP. Click on that and it will download. Again, I already have it downloaded just for this video. One more time you want to extract that into a folder. Then once you open up this folder you will see a bunch of files and these files aren&amp;#39;t useful to you. The only thing you need here is you&amp;#39;re going to need to create a dot bat file which will allow you to start mining.
&lt;p&gt;But before we do that, you will need to join a pool. And a pool is basically just a group of miners that mine together in order to find coins faster. So a good website to find some good pools is Dogepool.com. And I&amp;#39;ll have a link in my video description. And really you can pick any of these pools. It doesn&amp;#39;t matter. There&amp;#39;s really no big difference between them. So just for this video I&amp;#39;m going to go with TeamDoge, but you know, it&amp;#39;s up to you which one you chose.
&lt;p&gt;So then you want to create an account and you&amp;#39;re going to need a user name, password, you&amp;#39;re email and a pin. And a pin is a four digit number and you want to make sure that that you remember this or write it down somewhere because you&amp;#39;re going to need this to get your Dogecoins from the pool into your wallet. So this is a very important number. Once you registered, it&amp;#39;s going to ask you to log in. So I already created an account.
&lt;p&gt;Okay. Once you logged in, you&amp;#39;re going to see a bunch of information on your dashboard. This should be zero. I&amp;#39;m not sure why it&amp;#39;s showing me a number. That&amp;#39;s strange. Okay. So once you&amp;#39;re on your dashboard, you&amp;#39;re going to want to do two things. First, you want to go to your workers tab. And here you want to create a worker. As you can see I already made a test worker, but really it can be any name you want. Here is a test in test. So, we&amp;#39;ll just add test two, test two. So I just add another worker. Really you just want a worker for every separate computer or video cards that you&amp;#39;re using on a pool. You don&amp;#39;t have to, but it lets you see which computers or video cards are performing the best and if there&amp;#39;s something wrong with one them you&amp;#39;ll know which exactly video card or computer that it is that is malfunctioning.
&lt;p&gt;So once you&amp;#39;ve done that. Now, we&amp;#39;re going to want to go back to our CG Miner folder. So here you&amp;#39;re going to want to right click. Go to new, new text document. And let&amp;#39;s call this start -- I guess I already have that. Weekend mining. It doesn&amp;#39;t matter what you call it. Then let&amp;#39;s open it with your text editor. And you&amp;#39;re going to want to copy this into this file. Okay. Also you&amp;#39;re going to need to replace a couple things here.
&lt;p&gt;In the username, Doge worker name. You&amp;#39;re going to want to replace it with a username of your pool and the worker name in your pool like we just made. So for me it would be how to mine doge dot test2 and for the password you&amp;#39;re going to need to put in the password that you just made for the worker. So again here it&amp;#39;s going to be test two.
&lt;p&gt;For the second part, you&amp;#39;re going to want to go back to your pool. Click on getting started and copy this part right here. It will be under the command liner instructions. And this a URL that your miner will navigate to to start mining. And again you want to just replace this part right here. And paste that in. Okay. So then you want to save this file and close it. Now, so here right now it is a text file, but we want this to be a dot bat file, B-A-T. So simply just rename it. Here dot bat. Click yes and now you have your bat file.
&lt;p&gt;Now to start mining, simply double click on this bat file. And there we go. It&amp;#39;s beginning to mine. Currently I&amp;#39;m using a Radeon 7850 video card and it should get around 330 kilo hashes per second. So this is going to slowly make it up there and then okay. Yeah, there we go. Now it&amp;#39;s at 300 kilo hashes. If you&amp;#39;re not sure how much your video card should be making, how many hashes it should be generating, simply google litecoin mining hardware. There we go. In the Litecoin wiki just simply google mining hardware comparison for Litecoin and here is a list of different GPUs and how many kilo hashes they should be getting.
&lt;p&gt;So if I search this page for 7850, you can see that people get between 340 and 300 or 411. Wow. So they get around 350 kilo hashes per second. And I&amp;#39;m getting about 310. So, that&amp;#39;s good. I mean, you can optimize it further and you can simply use the settings that they have right here. As you can see right now, I&amp;#39;m running on a lower intensity. So this way I can use the computer while I&amp;#39;m mining. Okay.
&lt;p&gt;And then the final part is once you start mining, just go back to your pool. Click on edit account and you&amp;#39;re going to want to open up your wallet and click in to the much received tab. You &amp;#39;r going to want to create a new address. Call that the name of your pool or whatever. And just right click on it, copy the address, go back into your pool and input that address into your payment address. And then you can set automatic payment threshold. 1,000 Doge is the smallest limit. Here we go. And then you just want to put in your pin. And there we go. Now it&amp;#39;s up to the account details. And if we go back into our dashboard, we can see that eventually it will update with the new hash rate.
&lt;p&gt;Now, quick note before we leave is that the hash rate that you see in CG Miner is always going to be much more precise than the hash rate that you see in the pool, because a pool calculates it using the shares over time and because this value can fluctuate so does the hash rate. When in reality your hash rate remains the same. So as long as you&amp;#39;re sure that your worker is working correctly. And then you don&amp;#39;t have to worry about the hash rate that it shows inside your pool. As long as it&amp;#39;s, you know, within 20% accuracy. All right. So it&amp;#39;s going to be a bit slow to update, but eventually it will update to the fairly precise kilo hash per second. And you&amp;#39;ll get paid out in next time you hit your minimum pay out. Okay. Well, I hope you enjoy this video on how to mine Dogecoin. If you liked it feel free to donate Doge coin to my address in the video description. And as always don&amp;#39;t forget to share this video, because the more people use Dogecoin the higher the value will go.
&lt;p&gt; All right, thanks and happy mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - Dogecoin Mining on Mac&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All right.  So I&amp;#39;m going to walk you through how to start mining Dogecoin.  The first thing you need to do is join a pool and right now I&amp;#39;m using poolerino.  It&amp;#39;s the most popular one.  There&amp;#39;s tons you can find online that doesn&amp;#39;t really matter.  The first thing you need to do is click a sign up button.  That will take you to this page where you can register account. There&amp;#39;s a number of fields you have to fill out.
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not going to do it for you because I already have an account.  So I&amp;#39;m just going to go in menu, login.  All right.  So this is what the inside of the mining pool website looks like.  The only thing you really need to do to here to get started is create a new worker.  You can do that clicking the My Workers thing.  You&amp;#39;ll see I&amp;#39;ve got a couple of workers here.  You can add a new worker with this tab on the side.  I&amp;#39;m going to make another one.  Just call it something worker 2.  And when you add that worker, you&amp;#39;ll see that it successfully gets added and you now have a new worker.  So it&amp;#39;s pretty much all we need to worry about here.  And there are few things you need to remember when you get to later steps.
&lt;p&gt;The first is your username, which in my case is Ardo.  Also, your worker name, which is worker 2 and your worker password, which in this case is also worker 2.  We&amp;#39;re going to use these later.  The only other thing you need to know is the host name, which you can find out at this home tab.  If you scroll all the way to the bottom in that homepage you&amp;#39;ll see it&amp;#39;s in this comment. But you want this, you should probably go ahead and copy that and we&amp;#39;ll use that later.  All right.  So the next thing you need to do is download the actual software to do the mining that available at SourceForge, and it&amp;#39;s called CPU miner. Go ahead and download that. The link&amp;#39;s in the description.  It will start your download and while this is going, let&amp;#39;s go over to finder, check out our Downloads folder.  You&amp;#39;ll see that it&amp;#39;s a zip file, so you&amp;#39;re going to need to expand that.  So go ahead and double-click that, it will expand, you&amp;#39;ll see this minerd executable, which is basically the program that we&amp;#39;re going to run to mine.
&lt;p&gt;Now to run this, we need to use an application called Terminal.  You can find that in your applications folder under Utilities.  It should be all the way at the bottom here, yep, double click it.  You&amp;#39;ll open up a Terminal, it looks like this.  If you&amp;#39;re not comfortable with it that&amp;#39;s fine, I&amp;#39;m going tell you exactly what&amp;#39;s you need to type to get this running, then you start with cd downloads, which is going to take you into the Downloads folder, basically, which is where that minerd file is.
&lt;p&gt;You then need to change the permissions on minerd.  So you type chmod 755 minerd, which is going to allow you to run the file.  And then you&amp;#39;re ready to run it, you need to dot, slash, minerd.  The first thing you need is dash O and then you paste that host name that you copied earlier.  And then the only other thing you need is user pass, dash, dash, userpass and you need to set that equal to their user name, which in my case was Ardo, dot, your worker name, which was worker 2 for me and then a colon and your worker password, which was also worker 2.
&lt;p&gt;And then you hit enter and your program is running, you&amp;#39;re now mining with your CPU.  Right.  So I just fast forward about twenty minutes.  It&amp;#39;s been running for twenty minutes now.  You&amp;#39;ll see it&amp;#39;s still going that the hash rate is a little bit higher.  More importantly, you see these accepted messages which means that you are generating valid Dogecoins.
If you zoom out and you go back to that pool website and refresh it, you can confirm that it&amp;#39;s working there, as well.  This might take a little bit.  But when you go back, you&amp;#39;ll see hash rate on your dashboard as well as a number of valid coins that you&amp;#39;ve produced.  There you have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - Dogecoin Mining on Windows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey everybody. So there&amp;#39;s a new cryptocurrency on the block. It&amp;#39;s called Dogecoin. And Dogecoin is basically a script based coin. So it&amp;#39;s a bit like Litecoin, I guess, you could say. And the maximum amount of coins that can be mined is around 100 billion. So, basically I don&amp;#39;t see any huge advantage to Dogecoin in terms of, you know, its technology compared to other script based coins. But the branding is pretty cool, because I think it&amp;#39;s the first the coins that&amp;#39;s branded off of a popular internet meme, the Doge meme. So I think that will give it a lot of advantage, you know, in terms of how popular it will get. As you can see here it&amp;#39;s released like on December 8th, which was like a week ago or something from when I made this video. And it already has 162 pages on its thread on bitcointalk.org so that alone shows a lot about its popularity at this point.
&lt;p&gt;And yeah basically, if you want to get started mining Dogecoins, first thing you got to do is download the wallet. And the wallet you can get from here. I&amp;#39;ll have the download link in the description for this version and I&amp;#39;ll also have a link to this thread here so you can check out for any updates on the Dogecoin software or other related issues. So once you&amp;#39;ve downloaded the zip file, you want to either make a new folder, you know, move it in there and then extract to a folder so that you get like a new folder for Dogecoin. And then you copy the folder and you -- yeah you copy the folder down to like program files or something wherever you want to store it and then you rename over there to like Dogecoin because may be you don&amp;#39;t want this extra stuff here. And then you go inside the folder. You make a shortcut to your desktop of the Dogecoin-QT.exe. You make a shortcut to your desktop and then you start the wallet software.
&lt;p&gt;Once you started the wallet software you go to a much receive. Here is the place where you can make new addresses and you click on new address. And this is a mining pool pay out address that we&amp;#39;re going to make here. So you type in your label like Dogecoin mining pool payout, for example. Then you click okay. I&amp;#39;m not going to do that because I already have an address here. And yeah, you copy the address. You&amp;#39;re going to right click, copy address. Then what you want to do is sign up for a pool. And there&amp;#39;s number of a Dogecoin pools already, but I just chose this one because it was first on the list.
&lt;p&gt;So, this is Doge.scriptpools.com. I&amp;#39;m sure there is other good pools out there and you&amp;#39;re going to have to look for them yourself, but this is just to illustrate an example so. And I think this pool is pretty good as well so. Should be okay. Then you go here to sign up. Click on sign up. And you enter your details. Enter your details, username, password, and it does require an email but it does not require verifications. You don&amp;#39;t have to click on anything in your inbox and then you enter your pin code and you should remember your pin code. Actually, you&amp;#39;re going to need that in a bit. And then you go and log in to the mining pool. And you go to edit account. Logged me out. I&amp;#39;m going to have to log in again.
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, so you go in here, into your account and click on edit account. And here you enter the payment address so. And then you give a certain percentage donation. I would recommend that it&amp;#39;s only a little bit so like a half percent at least. And then you have your automatic payment threshold. So 10,000 is the minimum on this mining pool. And then here at the bottom you enter your four digit pin number and click update accounts. And the payment address should appear here. And yeah, so then after that you got to make a worker. Go to my workers and you type in like a number here like number one. Like, I have number one and X or XO or whatever. And then you want to make a note of this. This is like the worker ID. And this is the password. So you want to make a note of this. They&amp;#39;re not, you know, super-secret or anything. They&amp;#39;re just, you know, so you can log stuff and yeah you can. It&amp;#39;s basically for mining with standalone mining apps.
&lt;p&gt;So the next thing you want to do once you made your worker is download the mining software. And there is basically two ways you can mine for Dogecoins. Number one is or the first one is CPU mining. So you mine with your microprocessor, but that&amp;#39;s usually not that effective alone if done alone so. But you can, you know, try it out as well so. You can get the CUP miner from this thread here. I&amp;#39;ll have it linked in the description. And here is the 32/64 bit miners. And the second way is through graphics card mining or GPU mining with your graphics card. And for Radeon graphic cards and other AMD graphics cards you&amp;#39;re going to want to use CG Miner. And the newer versions of CG miners don&amp;#39;t support script which is the algorithm that the Dogecoin is based on. But this older ones or slightly older ones support it. It’s 3.6.6 for example. That&amp;#39;s a decent version. You go to this link that I&amp;#39;ll have linked and you click on View Raw and you&amp;#39;ll get to download the zip file.
&lt;p&gt;And if you&amp;#39;re running NVidia GeForce or other NVidia graphics card and you&amp;#39;re going to want use CudaMiner and you can get it from this thread at bitcointalk.org, which will also be linked in the description. And here is the zip file. It has both 32 and 64 bit versions in it. So you can just download that and extract it and pick the version that suits you the best. Then once you&amp;#39;ve done that you&amp;#39;re going to want to make this batch files. Basically these batch files, they configure the mining software where it&amp;#39;s going to mine and you know the username details and stuff like that. So you, yeah, you need to make those and to make those you just open up your Notepad. Then you copy this stuff in there. And you enter your details like your username and then the worker Id which was number 1 and then the worker password which I had as X.
&lt;p&gt;So all this are pretty much the same because they&amp;#39;re all based off of I think the CPU miner. So they&amp;#39;re like structure or the format is pretty much the same.  Except for CG Miner which is not a script miner by default. So you need to enable like script mining by putting this additional thing here. But otherwise it&amp;#39;s exactly the same as other two. And I&amp;#39;ll have this linked as well in the descriptions so you can like copy then directly as well.
&lt;p&gt;
And, yeah, basically these have to be in the same folder as the mining software. So it has to be in the same folder as the executable like CudaMiner.exe or minerde.exe which is the CPU Miner or CG miner. And when you want to run your miner, you run it off the batch file. You don&amp;#39;t run it off the executable, because then it doesn&amp;#39;t get configured. So when you make shortcuts, you want to make shortcuts to the BAT file instead of the executable. And that&amp;#39;s how you run it.
&lt;p&gt;
Yeah. That&amp;#39;s all I have for this video. If you have any questions just ask them in the comment section. I&amp;#39;ll try my best to answer them and yeah, that&amp;#39;s all. So happy mining and I&amp;#39;ll see you all later. Bye!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-dogecoin-mining/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-dogecoin-mining/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Banks and Brokerages Should Be Mining The Blockchain</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The biggest new trend I am seeing in bitcoin/blockchain is the emergence of a number of companies building systems on the blockchain (including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nasdaq.com/press-release/nasdaq-launches-enterprisewide-blockchain-technology-initiative-20150511-00485&quot;&gt;the NASDAQ&lt;/a&gt;) to handle the backoffice issues that banks and brokerage firms have to manage. The blockchain is an ideal platform to build these sorts of applications (clearing, settlement, etc) on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One concern I hear, though, is that banks like to know who is managing their infrastructure and they are uncomfortable with miners they don&amp;#8217;t know, located in parts of the world that make them nervous, providing the transaction processing infrastructure for these applications being built on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, that is the perfect reason for banks and brokerage firms to take a bit of their data processing infrastructure and point it to the blockchain and start mining it. They could even create a mining pool among the large money center banks. And it is relatively simple for a blockchain application to route its transactions to certain miners to process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think of the blockchain as an open source, peer to peer, massively distributed database, then it makes sense for the transaction processing infrastructure for it to evolve from individuals to large global corporations. Some of these miners will be dedicated for profit miners and some of them will be corporations who are mining to insure the integrity of the network and the systems they rely on that are running on it. Banks and brokerage firms are the obvious first movers in the second category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wonder if the CIOs of the large money center banks are already doing this. If I was in their jobs, I would be all over this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/banks-and-brokerages-should-be-mining-the-blockchain/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/banks-and-brokerages-should-be-mining-the-blockchain/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is DASH mining?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weusecoins.com/what-is-dashcoin/&quot;&gt;What is DASH?&lt;/a&gt; Darkcoin was rebranded as DASH. Want to learn how to mine DASH? First, mining DASH is done via scrypt instead of SHA256.
&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tNpEmo3y0VQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started mining DASH you could get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/70khsdogecoinminer&quot;&gt;70KHs DASH miner&lt;/a&gt; for about $100 or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/30mhslitecoinminer&quot;&gt;30MHs DASH miner&lt;/a&gt; for about $285.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - How to Mine Darkcoin -- The GUI Friendly Simple way of mining Dark Coin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;#39;m going to show you how to mine Darkcoins. You are going to go to how to mine Darkcoins.  So, little bit quickly what Darkcoins is, it&amp;#39;s an alt cryptocurrency, a lot like bitcoins but it has more kind of anonymous kind of built into the coin itself.  So it&amp;#39;s – while bitcoin can be traced very easily where it&amp;#39;s going back and forth darkcoin is kind of a little bit more privacy orientated.  So, it&amp;#39;s a CPU coin but it can also be graphics card or GPU mined.  So, today I&amp;#39;m going to show you how to CPU coin mine it and GPU coin mine it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first thing you want to do is disable your antivirus.  Reason for that is if we actually download the Darkcoin wallet or the mining software it’s going to pick it up as a virus.  I’ll just actually show you right here.  I get a link to the wallet and if I go here to download it, Norton comes up saying it&amp;#39;s not safe and it automatically deletes it.  So the first thing we’re going to do is just disable Norton whatever your antivirus is.  Let&amp;#39;s go for an hour, disable that.  So, now we&amp;#39;re going to actually download the wallet.  So, let’s get the latest version and I would just recommend going right to Darkcoin’s website.  Go to download, get your OS and download the wallet.  All right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;#39;s like an auto remove like I did before.  So it should just go through and install.  I already have it installed here.  And as you could see I got a couple of coins already mined with the software.  So we know it works.  Two coins here.  So what we want to do now is we&amp;#39;re going to get the receive address where we&amp;#39;re going to receive the coins into.  So, you&amp;#39;re going to go to receive.  This is your address here.  You&amp;#39;re going to right click on that and hit copy address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have copied the receive address next thing we want to do is we want to get this simple CPU mining software installed.  It provided a couple of different links, Dropbox, Zip file.  The installer install a little bit easier so we just recommend downloading installer.  The Zip file will work too but it won&amp;#39;t auto start up the windows so you&amp;#39;ll have to manually start up every time you restart your computer.  So, on this I&amp;#39;m going to click more info and run anyway.  What that is saying is it&amp;#39;s not a program that should run a lot so Windows doesn&amp;#39;t know what it is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we&amp;#39;re going to hit run anyway.  And now you want to just go through and hit next, next, next and install the software.  I&amp;#39;ve already installed it so I&amp;#39;m just going to cancel that.  And once it is installed you&amp;#39;re going to get something like this that shows up.  What you want to do is you want to go down here and you want to find Darkcoin.  So, now that you&amp;#39;ve found the coin.  We&amp;#39;re actually going to just test make sure it works.  So actually I&amp;#39;m going to put in that address we copied before.  I&amp;#39;m going to highlight this and I&amp;#39;m going to paste my address in there.  So you want your address to go into the receive coin address.  That&amp;#39;s step one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we&amp;#39;re going to go over here, make sure that start program invisible is unchecked.  We&amp;#39;re going to run it idle and not idle so running the software 24x7 and we&amp;#39;re going to hit run.  Next, the DOS screen should pop up.  It did and it&amp;#39;s starting to mine right here.  So, that means everything is working properly.  This is accepted.  That&amp;#39;s great.  So it&amp;#39;s working.  So, what I&amp;#39;m going to do is I’m going to stop this now.  Basically, I’m going to go back to settings now what I like to do is just run in the background so I change this to idle.  So, when I&amp;#39;m not using the system or walk away from it it&amp;#39;s going to start mining so I choose idle.  We&amp;#39;re going to run it invisibly.  And then I&amp;#39;m going to just double check and verify that that is my receive address, which it is.  And now you can save that and then you can hit run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as you can see Donald here is mining away.  So when I walk away from my computer it&amp;#39;s going to start mining, come back shake the mouse it&amp;#39;s going to stop mining.  It will run 24x7 and as long as I leave my computer on it&amp;#39;s going to run.  So, let&amp;#39;s see what else we have here.  Okay.  We do want to exclude this from the scans.  As soon as your Norton comes back on and does its scan it&amp;#39;s going to remove all the mining software and the wallet.  So what we&amp;#39;re going to do is I&amp;#39;m going to show you on Norton.  It might be a little bit different for your particular antivirus.  You can do some Google searches and see how to do it but basically it&amp;#39;s going to be you’re going to exclude certain folder from the scans.  The folder we want to exclude from the scans is this C program files folder right here.  So, you&amp;#39;re going to browser to it and there’s going to be another C program files and should be called miner.  Here it is right here miner.  So, I&amp;#39;m going to check off that and when I exclude that I&amp;#39;m going to copy this and exclude it from the scans, which I already have.  And you want to exclude it also from auto protect.  And folder, put the folder in, exclude and I already have so that&amp;#39;s good.  So, now that I’ve excluded it you can re-enable your antivirus and it shouldn&amp;#39;t fight the mining software at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do want to show you here is also the GPU or graphics way to mine it.  You can GPU and CPU mine simultaneously and it should mine just fine.  As far as performance, if you have a good graphics card generally you&amp;#39;re going to get more coins with a graphics card than, you know, just CPU mining depending on your chip and everything like that.  But if you have a good graphics card I would recommend GPU mining also.  So, I&amp;#39;m going to show you this software it&amp;#39;s very similar.  It’s just a black icon instead so you&amp;#39;re going to download it, install, next, next, next.  It&amp;#39;s going to pop up.  You&amp;#39;re going to go down here to Darkcoin, you’re going to paste in your address.  Okay.  Paste that address, the receive address, same one I showed you before, right under receive.  And you&amp;#39;re going to go over here to settings.  You&amp;#39;re going to just run, make sure it runs.  This one looks a bit little different, you will see, but it is mining so that&amp;#39;s good.  Now that we know that it&amp;#39;s mining we can hide it, we can run it when it&amp;#39;s idle and we can save that and we can run.  Then you can close the program out.  It doesn&amp;#39;t have to be running in the background and then when you walk away it will start mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any problems with that, the DOS window doesn&amp;#39;t show up, follow these directions at the bottom, these you might sometimes need a specific driver in order to get it working, ATI driver 3.1.  You do need an ATI video card, generally a newer card usually in the last two or three years.  And you need this AMD SDK pack also.  So, it give you the directions here just click install, next, next, next, restart and it should work on there.  So, let me know if you have any questions.  If you like the video please give me a thumbs-up.  Also at the bottom here you can like, tweet and send me a comment if you have any questions about anything.  Yeah, and that&amp;#39;s about it.  Hope you like the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-dash-mining/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/what-is-dash-mining/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Antminer S5 and S3 - Bitcoin Mining Setup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The AntMiner S5 is about four times more powerful than the AntMiner S3 but otherwise they are very similiar. Have you purchased an &lt;A href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/1155ghsantminerbitcoinminer&quot;&gt;Antminer S3&lt;/a&gt; Bitcoin miner and need to learn how to set it up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;AntMiner S5 - Unboxing Bitcoin Miner Setup with Power Supply&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uNbaZwqdPAc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most Bitcoin miners will need power supplies to run and they can be expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Antminer S3 - Bitcoin Mining Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4RBt2LPMEZY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It should be pretty easy to setup your Bitcoin miner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How to Setup a Raspberry Pi 2 Bitcoin Mining Rig w/ Bitmain AntMiner U3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dPWTSytzN7g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bitcoin Mining Hardware Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, based on &lt;b&gt;(1)&lt;/b&gt; price per hash and &lt;b&gt;(2)&lt;/b&gt; electrical efficiency the best Bitcoin miner options are:
&lt;div id=&quot;tableMainWrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;tableWrapper&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;table id=&quot;vsTable&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;cat title&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;title&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;second&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;cat&quot; style=&quot;width: 280px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 281px;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/antminers7&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; src=&quot;/images/bitcoin-miner-antminer-s7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Antminer S5 Bitcoin Miner&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;133&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 280px;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/17thsspondooliesbitcoinminer&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; src=&quot;/images/bitcoin-miner-spondoolies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spoondoolies Bitcoin Miner&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;150&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 280px;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/2ghsbitfuryusbbitcoinminer&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; src=&quot;/images/bitcoin-miner-bitfury-usb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bitfury USB Bitcoin Miner&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;111&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;cat&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Manufacturer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;title&quot; class=&quot;a-size-large a-spacing-none&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; padding: 0px; margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-left: 0px; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; font-weight: 400; color: #111111; margin-bottom: 0px !important; font-size: 21px !important; line-height: 1.3 !important;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;productTitle&quot; class=&quot;a-size-large&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; line-height: 1.3 !important; font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;AntMiner S7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;title&quot; class=&quot;a-size-large a-spacing-none&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; padding: 0px; margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-left: 0px; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; font-weight: 400; color: #111111; margin-bottom: 0px !important; font-size: 21px !important; line-height: 1.3 !important;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;productTitle&quot; class=&quot;a-size-large&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; line-height: 1.3 !important; font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;Spondoolies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 class=&quot;a-size-large a-spacing-none&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; padding: 0px; margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-left: 0px; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; font-weight: 400; color: #111111; margin-bottom: 0px !important; font-size: 21px !important; line-height: 1.3 !important;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;productTitle&quot; class=&quot;a-size-large&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; line-height: 1.3 !important; font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;Tech SP20 Jackson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;title&quot; class=&quot;a-size-large a-spacing-none&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; padding: 0px; margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-left: 0px; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; font-weight: 400; color: #111111; margin-bottom: 0px !important; font-size: 21px !important; line-height: 1.3 !important;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;productTitle&quot; class=&quot;a-size-large&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; line-height: 1.3 !important;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.3;&quot;&gt;BPMC Red Fury USB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;a-size-large&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; line-height: 1.3 !important;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 class=&quot;a-size-large a-spacing-none&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; padding: 0px; margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-left: 0px; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; font-weight: 400; color: #111111; margin-bottom: 0px !important; font-size: 21px !important; line-height: 1.3 !important;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;productTitle&quot; class=&quot;a-size-large&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; line-height: 1.3 !important;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;second&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;cat&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Advertised Capacity&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;4,730 Gh/s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;1,500 GH/s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.5 GH/s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;cat&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Power Efficiency&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.25 W/Gh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.80 W/Gh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.00 W/Gh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;second&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;cat&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weight&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;8.8 pounds&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;20 pounds&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.6 ounces&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class=&quot;second&quot;&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;cat&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Getting Started Guide&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/antminer-s3-bitcoin-miner-setup/&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/spondoolies-tech-SP20-bitcoin-miner-setup/&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/usb-bitcoin-miner-setup-guide/&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;cat&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Price&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;$2,400.00&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/antminers7&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Buy Antminer S7 bitcoin miner&quot; src=&quot;/images/buy-from-amazon.png&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;28&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;$499.97&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/17thsspondooliesbitcoinminer&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Buy Spondoolies bitcoin miner&quot; src=&quot;/images/buy-from-amazon.png&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;28&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;$33.87&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.runtogold.com/2ghsbitfuryusbbitcoinminer&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Buy Bitfury bitcoin miner&quot; src=&quot;/images/buy-from-amazon.png&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;28&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;cat&quot; style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Appx. BTC Earned Per Month&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.9153&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.2902&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;width: 25%;&quot; class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.00077463&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - Antminer S5 - Bitcoin Mining Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello.  We got a power supply here.  I just got it from Newegg.  That’s my power supply to my miner here.  I’ll show you how to jump it real quick.  Alright, so take a paper clip and you connect the green and the black wire there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s pretty simple.  You shove it in there -- just like so and make sure it&amp;#39;s the green and the black and then you can take some duct tape, wrap it up, good to go -- or electrical tape.  And then we got the miner here, BitMiner.  The pack is pretty good.  So, there’s that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using that cord -- goes in here and this then obviously goes to your modem or router whatever you’re using.  And then each board here gets one cord.  Not like this -- like this.  It&amp;#39;s plugged into the PCIe slots on the power supply.  I’m just going to unplug this for the moment.  And it&amp;#39;s going, got lights.  It just needs to be hooked up to the internet and it’ll start running away.  Done deal -- that easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so here&amp;#39;s my two miners all set up going.  I got two power supplies on top.  They’re both the same thing.  Raidmax, 80 gold, 1000 watt, four rails a piece.  That&amp;#39;s what these things require.  So, you see the temperature there, now it&amp;#39;s 86, oh, 76.  Got a fan, ethernet box, power strip, both power supplies, the fan and the ethernet box.  Doing about 1309, the wattage is 1310 for both of them, everything you see there and putting the fan on low.  So that&amp;#39;s it, making money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, so this is the miner, it&amp;#39;s going about 2 hours 10 minutes, 2 hours 16 minutes and we&amp;#39;re updating it.  See average speed, temperature is down there 48 to 50.  That&amp;#39;s like the average miner status if you look at anything.  All the other tabs are pretty much junk.  There’s an advance section but, you know, it just turns it up and all you can do is create more heat.  It’s not really going to hash that much faster.  I actually have it bumped up to the next tier and there we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there is that one and here&amp;#39;s the second one.  It&amp;#39;s going 4 days 9 minutes and it&amp;#39;s probably little longer 15 minutes.  There’s the average speed over that time frame.  And here&amp;#39;s temperature, you see they’re right next to each other so here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - Antminer S3 - Bitcoin Mining Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey what’s up guys, this is Randall with Off The Grid Survival.  This is going to be a quick video on my Bitcoin mining set up.  I&amp;#39;m currently running three AntMiner S3 Bitcoin miners which are powered by two 750 watt power supplies.  A little information on these Bitcoin miners each AntMiner S3 is generating around 450 gigahash per second which gives me a grand total of 1.35 terahashes per second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright guys, so here&amp;#39;s the overview of the AntMiner setup.  I got this set up in my spare bedroom of my house.  I have it hooked up to a five-port switch, that&amp;#39;s seen off to the left of the screen there’s a little network switch.  Three AntMiners are powered by two Corsair CX750M power supplies.  And like I said right now they are just hashing away as you can hear they&amp;#39;re a little bit on the noisy side, but that&amp;#39;s expected with Bitcoin mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, one of the big questions that I&amp;#39;m probably going to get is how much does all these cost?  Grand total I would say these cost may be around $500.  These AntMiner S3s you can get a pretty good deal on ebay forum because a lot of the big AntMiner farms that are out there they&amp;#39;re trading in their S3s and they are upgrading to the AntMiner S5.  So, you can get a great deal on these things on ebay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I have maybe around $500 tied into this.  I used my Google Adsense Revenue which was around $330 last year to purchase a majority of these.  So, I am only out of pocket maybe around $150 on these AntMiners.  Overall, I&amp;#39;m very pleased with them.  They are making money, they are doing what they&amp;#39;re paid to do and that is hash with a SHA256 scrypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright guys, so for more details on Bitcoin mining I am going to link a video on the description from Barnacules Nerdgasm’s channel.  It&amp;#39;s a great video on Bitcoin mining and I&amp;#39;m going to link that in the description below.  All right, so now you&amp;#39;re probably asking yourself should I start mining Bitcoins?  And it&amp;#39;s not a cut-and-dried answer.  It&amp;#39;s depending on where you live and what the cost of your power is where you are located.  It is tactical, what you&amp;#39;re doing is you&amp;#39;re buying Bitcoins through your power bill by mining these Bitcoins.  This -- if you do get into it do it as a hobby, this is not a get rich quick scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, if you do get into Bitcoin mining, the first thing that you&amp;#39;re going to need is a Bitcoin wallet.  The website I like to use is coinbase.com.  It&amp;#39;s basically like a Bitcoin version of Pay Pal.  It&amp;#39;s a place where you store your Bitcoins, you could sell Bitcoins, buy Bitcoins etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s an example of my coinbase account.  Now one thing you need to be made aware of when dealing with Bitcoins is the market for Bitcoins is very volatile.  It is always -- there&amp;#39;s lots of ups and downs so that&amp;#39;s one thing you need to take into consideration if you want to start mining Bitcoins.  Alright guys, so one last thing with the coinbase account is if you ever want to sell your Bitcoins and convert those into US dollars you can easily do so by just linking your bank account information clicking the sell button and you&amp;#39;ll have US currency in your account a day or two later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright guys, a little bit more on my Bitcoin miners.  I do have them working in a mining pool.  And a mining pool is thousands of people that are working together to mine together to find a block, and a block consists of 25 bitcoins and if you find that one block the profits are split between all the people that are mining for that pool, I mean mining for that block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the site that I use is btcguild.com.  It works out very well for me.  As you can see I&amp;#39;m getting regular payouts of .01 Bitcoins almost daily.  Some of the days where I have lapses in my Bitcoins I was swapping over to a different pool like Slush’s pool or Bitcoin Affiliate Network.  And I just went back to btcguild and I&amp;#39;m sticking with it.  Now, in closing probably one of the final questions I&amp;#39;m going to get is why am I Bitcoin mining -- mining for Bitcoins?  And why did I choose to go this route and spend this type of money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I really didn&amp;#39;t have that much money invested, like I said, $330 I got last year from Google Adsense Revenue which has dropped considerably ever since they switched to the Google Plus thing but I&amp;#39;m not going to really get into that whole aspect though because I don’t make these videos to make money.  That’s just an extra part I would say.  Pretty much, I like the fact that Bitcoins are not centralized to any government or corporation.  It&amp;#39;s all decentralized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much anything that I do with Bitcoins can be off the record.  I can also take that Bitcoins, convert it into US currency and purchase silver or any type of precious metal that I want.  So that&amp;#39;s pretty much why I mine for Bitcoins.  It&amp;#39;s just something cool that I wanted to do.  I just want to dabble in it.  I really don’t have to defend the matter on why I&amp;#39;m doing it.  I&amp;#39;m just doing it.  So, alright guys, I hope you enjoy the video.  This is Randall with Off The Grid Survival.  I&amp;#39;m out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript - How to Setup a Raspberry Pi 2 Bitcoin Mining Rig w/ Bitmain AntMiner U3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s up guys?  I’m Rasim from Rasmurtech.com and today I&amp;#39;m going to show you guys how to use a Raspberry Pi 2 to mine Bitcoin with our AntMiner U3.  This is the Bitmain AntMiner U3 and this is a 60 gigahash miner this is ASIC miner.  And again, we&amp;#39;re going to use our Raspberry Pi as the node and it&amp;#39;s going to control our AntMiner and we&amp;#39;re going to mine Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the first thing you&amp;#39;re going to need is a Raspberry Pi.  It can be any Raspberry Pi but I&amp;#39;m using the Raspberry Pi 2.  Now I know you guys are wondering what the hell is going on.  This is a stackable case and I have four Raspberry Pis here.  Now I set this up because I&amp;#39;m working on another video where I -- where I cluster these into a cluster computer and I compare them to my other Raspberry Pi B cluster and we do speed test to compare the two so I obviously took that deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, before we can move forward we have to set this up.  The way we set it up is connect the internet to your Raspberry Pi connect the other into your router.  Connect via USB -- this USB cord connect it to your AntMiner U3.  All right.  Then also, you’re going to want to connect this mini or micro USB port here to the Raspberry Pi.  Then make sure that the other end is connected to a powered hub, alright, or has a powered source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you&amp;#39;re going to connect the AntMiner&amp;#39;s power, this is the power for the AntMiner, right?  And it should start -- start up.  The fans should start up and it&amp;#39;s powered on.  You know it&amp;#39;s powered on because the fans are spinning.  Alright, so now all we have to do is move on to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All right guys so now we&amp;#39;re going to set this thing up and actually get it to start mining.  Remember we&amp;#39;re using our Raspberry Pi 2.  You can use any Raspberry Pi for this tutorial.  But in this tutorial I&amp;#39;m using my Raspberry Pi 2 and we are connecting it to the AntMiner U3 so we could start mining Bitcoin.  So, we don’t need a computer.  All we need is our Raspberry Pi and AntMiner U3 and we&amp;#39;re good to go with mining Bitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing we&amp;#39;re going to need to do is open a puTTY and remotely access our Raspberry Pi.  Now if you don&amp;#39;t know what puTTY is, if you don’t know how to install Raspbian I did a video where I show you guys how to do that.  I&amp;#39;m going to leave that video in the description.  It&amp;#39;s called the Raspberry Pi cluster supercomputer but it&amp;#39;s Part 2.  In that video I show you how to install everything on Raspbian, how to find the IP address of your Raspberry Pi, how to install puTTY and how to remotely access it.  You need to know those things first before you can watch this video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if you know how to do all that stuff then you are good to go and you could follow with this video.  But again, I&amp;#39;m going to leave the link to that video in the description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first thing I want to do is open up puTTY and the IP address for my Raspberry Pi is 192.168.1.156, yours could be different.  If you don&amp;#39;t know it you&amp;#39;re going to need to find out.  You could find out by typing, if config in the terminal when Raspbian is loaded and it should show you your IP address.  So, now we are just going to click open here and it should start, click on yes.  Now it&amp;#39;s prompting us to enter a username.  The username is Pi, hit enter and the password is raspberry, so R A S P B E R R Y, hit enter.  It should start loading the Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the next step is to open up a web browser here and we&amp;#39;re going to navigate to this URL here.  I&amp;#39;m going to leave a link to this URL in the description.  But we&amp;#39;re going to scroll down till we get to this part here it&amp;#39;s by ajweller88.  He created an awesome tutorial and it&amp;#39;s a step-by-step tutorial and we are going to get to copy the code so we don’t have to type anything.  And again it&amp;#39;s by ajweller88 he created awesome tutorial.  And in this tutorial he shows us how to set up an AntMiner U3 and get it working on a Raspberry Pi.  This tutorial works on any Raspberry Pi but we&amp;#39;re using the Raspberry Pi 2.  You can use any Raspberry Pi you want and it should work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the first thing we need to do is copy the first line of code here sudo apt-get update copy this.  All right.  And when you get to this terminal here if you don&amp;#39;t know how to paste it all you have to do is right click your mouse and it should paste it automatically.  Then hit enter and let it run.  And now we’re going to copy the second line of code here sudo apt-get upgrade.  Copy that and paste it here and then hit enter.  And it should prompt you to continue with Y for yes N for no.  Type Y then hit answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are going to install dependencies.  To do that, copy this code here from sudo and up until the screen here.  Copy all that and paste it here, hit enter and it should prompt you to continue Y for yes N for no.  Type Y hit enter.  So, now we&amp;#39;re going to download the CG Miner that&amp;#39;s the mining software that will mine all the Bitcoin for us.  To do that we&amp;#39;re going to copy this code right here git clone and up until the miner here, this whole line of code.  Copy it and paste it on the terminal and hit enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;#39;re going to configure the CG Miner.  To do that we&amp;#39;re going to copy this first line of code here cd cgminer.  That&amp;#39;s going to change directory into the CG Miner directory.  Copy that and paste it and hit enter.  Now we&amp;#39;re going to copy the second line of code here sudo up until the sh here.  Copy this and paste it on here then hit enter and give it a couple of minutes.  When that’s finished we&amp;#39;re going to copy this third line of code here export LIBCURL up until this point here.  Copy this and paste it on to here then hit enter.  That&amp;#39;s done.  We&amp;#39;re going to copy the fourth line of code here and paste it on to here, hit enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All right now, we&amp;#39;re going to copy this line of code sudo make.  Copy it, paste it here and hit enter.  And now everything is installed.  Now we could test out whether or not it will work.  Right now we&amp;#39;re going to actually start mining and first thing we need to do is copy this bit of code here.  Now you need to fill in the blanks here.  Your pool you need to – where it says pool here you need to fill it in with your pool address and where it says username you need to fill it in with your username and where it says password here you need to fill this in with your password.  Right?  I opened up my text document here and I pasted that onto a text document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should paste it onto a text document and save it onto your desktop so that you could just copy it and paste it onto a terminal at any time whenever you want to run your mine.  But I replaced my pool here with my username, I’m sorry with my url.  This is my pool url.  I’m using slush’s pool.  I replaced my user with my username.  My username is rasim.worker1 and my password here is anything.  If you don&amp;#39;t know how to download a wallet, how to join a pool and how to create workers I&amp;#39;m going to leave that link to the video where I show you guys all that stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now once that&amp;#39;s done you just copy this from your text file.  Remember first thing you do is copy this here.  This bit of code here and copy it and paste it in a text editor, note pad or whatever you want to do.  Then paste or replace the pool with your pool address, the username with your worker name and the password with your password and then save it onto the desktop so you could just easily copy it and paste it when you need to.  So, now I&amp;#39;m going to copy this here and I&amp;#39;m going to paste it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember it can be filled in with your info, your pool address, your worker username and your worker password.  So, now all we have to do -- and when you paste this it has to be in the CG Miner directory -- cd to the root directory hit enter.  Now in the root directory if I paste this here and I hit enter it shouldn&amp;#39;t work.  See, it didn&amp;#39;t work.  So before you can paste this you’ll have to cd /home/pi/cgminer.  You have to be in the CG Miner directory before you can paste this code.  Once you paste this code here it&amp;#39;s going to start mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So once you hit enter it&amp;#39;s going to start mining for you, it should with your AntMiner U3 and remember you have to be connected to the Internet.  Your AntMiner U3 has to be connected to your Raspberry Pi and if everything was done successfully you should see your AntMiner here.  This is the actual AntMiner and it should start working and it&amp;#39;s working right now.  And it&amp;#39;s going to give you the gigahash or megahash rate that the miner is running.  Up here is how many gigahash or megahash you are running per second up here.  And if you see accepted like it did here that means it’s actually mining like you&amp;#39;re actually making Bitcoins now or actually mining Bitcoins now.  And that&amp;#39;s pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So again to exit all you have to do is type in Q.  Hit Q and it should shutdown.  And it should go back to terminal.  Remember it&amp;#39;s good to have this saved on any text documents.  So all you have to do is just copy the code and just paste it and it should start mining.  Again you have to be in the CG Miner directory.  I’m going to cd back into the root directory so I&amp;#39;ll show you again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So remember you have to cd /home/pi/cgminer hit enter to get back into the CG Miner directory or folder.  Then you could open up your text document and copy the code that will automatically start CG Miner and start mining for you then hit enter and it should start working.  It&amp;#39;s easier just to save in a text document.  So that&amp;#39;s pretty much it for this part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right guys so that’s pretty much it for this video.  If you guys like this video please give me a like.  If you want more videos like this please subscribe to my channel.  I&amp;#39;m Rasim from Rasmurtech.com and thanks for watching.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bitcoinmining.com/antminer-s3-bitcoin-miner-setup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bitcoinmining.com/antminer-s3-bitcoin-miner-setup/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>